片名：迈克尔·克莱顿
迈克尔
Michael.
亲爱的迈克尔，很显然是你，他们还能派谁过来？
Dear Michael. Of course it's you. Who else could they send?
还有谁值得信任？
Who else could be trusted?
我也知道你大老远地跑来很辛苦，而且你马上就要开始工作了
And I know it's a long way and you're ready to go to work.
但请听我说，等等、再等等、再… 让我把话说完
All I'm saying is wait, just wait, just­ Just please hear me out.
因为这不是什么小打小闹，也不是旧病复发，更不是什么胡搅蛮缠
Because this is not an episode, relapse, fuckup.
求你了，迈克尔，我求求你
I'm begging you, Michael, I'm begging you..
相信我吧，这不仅仅只是疯狂
Try and make believe this is not just madness­
…因为这绝不只是疯狂
­  because this is not just madness.
两周之前，我从这栋楼里出来，对吧？
Two weeks ago, I came out of the building, okay?
我跑过第六大街，有辆车等在那里…
I'm running across 6th Avenue, there's a car waiting­
…我必须在38分钟内到达机场，我边走边说
­  I got exactly 38 minutes to get to the airport, and I'm dictating.
我那慌里慌张的助手也手忙脚乱地在记事本上…
There's this panicked associate sprinting along beside me­
…写个不停，突然她叫了起来
­  scribbling in a notepad, and she starts screaming.
我猛地意识到我们正站在大街中央…
And I realize we're standing in the middle of the street­
…信号一变，汹涌的车辆向我们冲过来
­  the light's changed and there's this wall of serious traffic speeding towards us.
我僵住了，无法动弹
And I freeze. I can't move.
我突然被一种无法抵制的感觉所吞蚀
I'm suddenly consumed with the overwhelming sensation­
…我被些薄膜状的东西盖住了
­  that I'm covered with some sort of film.
它粘在我的头发上和脸上，它有点像蛋清，又像是某种涂层
And it's in my hair, in my face. And it's like a glaze, like a coating.
起初我想，噢，上帝呀，我知道这是什么了
And at first I thought, "Oh, my God, I know what this is.
这是羊膜，是流动的羊水
This is some sort of amniotic, embryonic fluid.
我正处于产后那湿漉漉的时刻
I'm drenched in afterbirth.
我刚刚破茧而出，我重生了
I've breached the chrysalis. I've been reborn. "
但随后，汹涌的车流、涌动的人群、轿车、卡车、警笛的尖叫
But then, the traffic, the stampede, the cars, the trucks, the horns­
…还有这可怜女人的尖叫，我想，不，这不是重生
­  this poor woman screaming, and I'm thinking, "No. This is not rebirth.
这只是一些恢复过程中的奇妙幻觉
This is some kind of giddy illusion of renewal­
…只是大限将至之前的幻觉
­  that happens in the final moment before death. "
然后我意识到“不、不、不，这一切都错了”…
And then I realize, "No, no, no, this is completely wrong"­
因为我回头再看那栋大楼…
­  because I looked back at the building­
…我突然醒悟了
­  and I had the most stunning moment of clarity.
迈克尔，我… 我意识到…
I realized, Michael­
我出来了，但不是通过肯纳、巴赫和莱迪恩的大门…
­  that I had emerged, not through the doors of Kenner, Bach & Ledeen­
不是我们那巨大无比的法律事务所的大门
­  not through the portals of our vast and powerful law firm­
而是通过一个有机体的屁眼…
­  but from the asshole of an organism­
这屁眼的唯一功能就是排出有毒物质…
­  whose sole function is to excrete the poison­
弹药和脱叶剂来给那些更大…
­  the ammo, the defoliant necessary for other larger­
…更强的公司用来摧毁人类文明的奇迹
­  more powerful organisms to destroy the miracle of humanity.
而在我生命中最美好的时刻…
And that I had been coated in this patina of shit­
…我也被涂上了一层这铜绿色的大便
­  for the best part of my life.
那东西的恶臭和污秽将使我的余生变得毫无意义
And the stench of it, the stain of it would take the rest of my life to undo.
你知道我做了些什么吗？
And you know what I did?
我深深地、彻底地吸了口气，把我那想法放到一边，我放下了它
I took a deep, cleansing breath and I set that notion aside. I tabled it.
我对自已说：很显然，这种强烈的感觉
I said to myself, "As clear as this may be, as potent a feeling as this is­
和我今天见证的东西一样真实，但它需要等待
­  as true a thing as I believe that I have witnessed today, it must wait.
它必须经受住时间的考验
It must stand the test of time. "
现在，迈克尔，时候到了
And, Michael, the time is now.
我想我能告诉的都已经告诉你了
I'm not sure what else I can tell you that I haven't already.
给我讲讲U/North公司的事，巴里，他们可是你们的客户
Tell me about U/North, Barry. They're your clients.
告诉我为什么你们大半夜的还在处理一件已经进行了6年的案子
So you tell me why you're settling a six-year-old case on the fly at midnight.
因为不管你愿不愿意，我都在报道这件事
Because I'm writing this story whether you like it or not.
你到底想怎么样？
What does that exactly mean?
给我报点儿料
Give me something I can print.
我们找到了97个
We found 97.
那个《华尔街日报》的婊子打到了我的手机上
I've got that cunt from The Wall Street Journal on my cell phone.
她不肯善罢甘休
She will not go away.
我是马蒂·巴赫，能帮上你什么忙吗？
Marty Bach. How can I help you?
马蒂，你好，我是布里奇特·克雷恩，我们打算明天刊登一篇…
Marty, hi. It's Bridget Klein. We're going with a story tomorrow­
…有关U/North公司除草剂事件解决方案的报导，你对此有何评论？
­  about a settlement in the U/North defoliant case. You wanna comment?
你所说的这桩诉讼，到现在已经审理了6年…
Case you're referring to is now, as it has been for the past six years­
…一直悬而未决
­pending and unresolved.
在我们的客户上法庭…
Till such time as our client has their day in court­
…或者原告撤诉之前我都无可奉告
­or the plaintiffs drop the suit, I'll have nothing of value to tell you.
得了，马蒂，你是最了解这件案子的人，我知道你现在正在处理这件案子
Come on, Marty, you're closing the U/North case. You're settling.
我还知道你那里现在有600人在忙这个案子
I know that. I know you're up there with 600 people jamming this thing through.
我所知道的是，你的截稿时间已经过了20分钟
Here's what I know. Your deadline was 20 minutes ago.
不管你是在忙着把故事写完还是忙着联系撤稿
So you're fishing for a story or trying to get out of writing a retraction.
无论是哪一样，我都祝你好运
In either case, I wish you the best of luck.
凯伦·克劳德死哪儿去了？
Where the fuck is Karen Crowder?
我跟
I'll see the turn.
不跟
Check.
半注，两百
Half the pot. Two hundred.
两百胜
Two hundred to go.
你不记得我了，哈？
You don't remember me, huh?
我们在一起玩过好几次
We played together a couple times.
在鲍威利区那个电灯屋
That lamp place on Bowery.
是那个家伙的商品陈列室吧？全是灯和其他乱七八糟的
That guy's showroom? All the lamps and shit?
-星河 -对，就是那儿
-The Galaxy -That's it.
你那时候还开了个餐馆，对吗？
You had a restaurant you were opening, right?
我过去的合伙人投标中了，负责管道
My old partner bid that job, the plumbing.
-你不记得我了？ -我记得你
-You don't remember me? -I remember you.
因为那之后我瘦了不少
Because I lost a lot of weight since then.
你也买了不少头发啊
You bought some hair too.
用的是你的钱
With your money.
那么，餐馆现在怎么样了？
So, what happened with the bar?
看来你经营的不善啊，哈？
You just had to be a rock star, huh?
操，哥们儿，还不如去听拉里·金(CNN主持人)呢，不玩了，回家看他妈的电视去
Shit, man. I want to listen to Larry King, I go home and put the fucking TV on.
那地点不错
That was a good location.
是呀，我的合伙人也是这么跟我说的
Yeah, that's what my partner kept telling me.
到你了
Action's on you.
我下底注
I bet the pot.
欢迎下次光临
Good to see you again.
喂？
Hello?
-是迈克尔吗？ -沃尔特吧
-Michael -Walter.
迈克尔，谢天谢地，总算找到你了，听着，我有点事情
Michael, thank God, there you are. Look, I got a situation.
出了个大事，明白么？我的一个客户他刚刚打电话给我，他开车撞了个人
A big problem, all right? A client of mine, he just called, he hit a guy with his car.
他觉得他撞了，他觉得他撞了个人
He thinks he did. He thinks he hit him.
就刚才？
Just now?
是的，就刚才，10、15分钟前，在他开车回家的路上
Yeah, just now. Ten, 15 minutes ago. He's driving home.
他现在在家，他在家里等你
He's home now. He's there waiting.
住哪儿？
Where?
西切斯特，我现在在百慕大这，我刚睡着就被他叫醒了
Westchester. I'm down here in Bermuda. He just got me up. I'm half asleep here.
他有没有喝酒？
Is he drunk?
没有，我一开口也是这么问他的，他精神很好，很清醒
No. It's the first thing I asked him. He's good, he's sober.
告诉他不要接任何电话了
Tell him to stay off the phone.
好的，你会去吧？你能去那儿吗？
All right. But you're on it? You can get up there?
这个家伙可是一个大客户
Because this guy, he's a huge client.
我大部份业务都是和他做的，好么？
This is half my book, this guy, okay?
我正走向车子
I'm walking to the car now.
好的，那么这样，我给他回个电话把地址搞到
Okay. Look, look, let me call him right back and I'll get the address.
你只要在路上就行了，我会给你带来更多的细节
Just let me know you're on the way, and I'll get back to you with the details.
好吧，我马上开车去
All right. I'll be in the car.
看看他们都做了些什么吧，你看，他们把路给升级了
What they did, see, they changed the grade there.
他们加宽了街道
They widened the street.
我想肯定有人告诉他们这个改进不错
I'm sure somebody told them that that was an improvement.
但现在，你看，一到阴天下雨或者碰上大雾，在这些新的拐角处
But now, you see, when it rains and when there is fog, and with this new angle­
他们搞的这些新的… 这些… 这些…
­and they've got these new­ These­  These­
这些高压钠灯，晃死人了
These sodium lamps, it's blinding.
-就那个拐角，很刺眼 -他们会想办法解决的
-That corner there. It is blinding -They'll have to work that out.
不只是今晚，我都和他们说了好几年了
And it's not just tonight. I've been saying this for years.
我说，我们讨论过那个拐弯多少次了？戴尔？
I mean, how many times have we talked about that corner? Dell?
格林先生，我们没有多少时间
Mr.Greer, we don't have a lot of time here.
那么周边环境、路况，所有这些情况你都不感兴趣喽？
So the circumstances, the road conditions, none of this holds any interest for you?
我感兴趣的是找到一个能在15分钟内到达的
What interests me is finding the strongest criminal attorney­
…优秀刑事辩护律师
­that can be here in 15 minutes.
哇噢，听起来好像不妙呀
Well, that sounds ominous.
在西切斯特，我们有些很好的关系
We have some good relationships up here in Westchester.
那么，你是干什么的？干什么的？你不是律师？
So, what are you? What are you? You're not a lawyer?
-不是你要的那种 -那你是哪种？
-Not the kind you need -What kind is that?
执业庭审律师
A trial lawyer.
有人能办理好这事，但我处理不了
Somebody who can see this through. That's not what I do.
好吧，看来我还是只能把沃尔特找回来处理了
Okay. I think we're gonna have to pull Walter back in on this.
我会给沃尔特打电话，把他搅和进来
I wanna get Walter back on the phone, get him back into the mix.
因为，和你直说了吧，我不喜欢现在这样
Because, I'll be frank with you, I don't like the way this is going.
先生，我们没时间等沃尔特了，你的选择范围正在快速地减小
Sir, we don't have time for Walter. Your options are gonna get smaller quickly.
什么选择范围？一个选项我都没听到！
What options? I'm not hearing any options!
我建议你还是到本地警局自首…
I suggest you go local­
…然后会有人来处理好这件事的
­and I'm telling you there are people here I like for this.
好极了，就那样吗？你就是这样帮我解决问题的吗？
Great. That's it? That's what you got for me?
嘿，你相信吗？
Hey, you believe this?
12年来，我一直都是你们肯纳、巴赫事务所的客户
I have been a client at Kenner, Bach for 12 years!
你认为我每月给你们付钱就是为了有朝一日能出庭受审？
You think I paid that retainer every month for a place at the back of the line?
格林先生，你在周日晚上离开一起事故的现场…
Mr.Greer, you left the scene of an accident on a slow weeknight­
…离州警局只有6英里远
­six miles from the state police barracks.
如果真要受审的话，你也快了
If there's a line, you're right up front.
我随时都可以再找个律师，我不需要你了
I can get a lawyer any time I want. I don't need you for that.
我们在这儿傻坐了45分钟就等来了这么一个白痴建议！
We're not sitting here for 45 minutes waiting for a goddamn referral!
我不知道沃尔特给了你什么承诺…
I don't know what Walter promised you­
一位天才员工！沃尔特在电话里是这么说的，就在20分钟前
A miracle worker! That's Walter on the phone, 20 minutes ago.
原话要听么，啊？“挺住，我会派一个天才来帮助你”
Direct quote, okay? "Hang tight. I'm sending you a miracle worker."
-喔，那他说错了 -哪儿说错了？
-Well, he misspoke -About what?
关于你是公司的救火员那部份？还是你根本就不在行？
That you're the firm's fixer? Or that you're good at it?
埃里奥特
Elliot.
那个家伙突然跑出来！在大马路上！
The guy was running! In the street!
你设想一下，大雾、路灯、还有那些转弯…
You take that, you add the fog, you add the lamps, you add the angle­
那个家伙大半夜的在街上跑个什么劲儿啊？！
What the fuck is he doing running in the middle of the street at midnight?!
你倒是说呀！
You answer me that!
说车被人偷了怎么样？
What if someone had stolen the car?
这种事常有的
Happens all the time.
警察们最喜欢处理这种交通肇事逃逸
Cops like hit-and-runs.
他们会快速利落地去办
They work them hard, they clear them fast.
现在犯罪现场调查部门正在从防撞护栏取走油漆样本
Right now there's a B.C.I. Unit pulling paint chips off a guard rail.
明天，他们就会开始寻找谁拥有涂有这种定制颜料的
Tomorrow, they're gonna be looking for the owner of a custom-painted­
…那辆手排档美洲虎XJ-12
­hand-rubbed Jaguar XJ-12.
还有你撞到的那个家伙？
And the guy you hit?
如果他看到了车牌的话，就更快了
If he got a look at the plates, it won't even take that long.
这样就玩完了
There's no play here.
再没有什么拐弯，也没有放香槟的房间
There's no angle. There's no champagne room.
我也不是什么天才，我就是个看门的
I'm not a miracle worker, I'm a janitor.
道理很简单
The math on this is simple.
麻烦越少，我处理起来就越容易
The smaller the mess, the easier it is for me to clean up.
警察打来的，是吗？
That's the police, isn't it?
不是
No.
他们是不会打的
They don't call.
喂
Hello.
杰瑞，我是迈克尔·克莱顿
Jerry, it's Michael Clayton.
对，是的，不好意思吵醒你了
Yeah, look, I'm sorry to wake you up.
不，我在你的隔壁
No. I'm in the neighborhood.
你有笔吗？
You got a pen?
(四天前)
妈妈，我的牌在哪儿？
Mom, where's my cards?
我的牌在哪儿呢？
Where's my cards?
我的另一幅牌在这儿不？
Is my other deck in here?
你吃了吗？
Did you eat?
爸爸已经在下面等着了
Dad's down there waiting already.
洗手间里有几副牌
There were cards in our bathroom.
吃了，我吃的瓦夫饼
Yes, I had a waffle.
那怎么可能，家里的瓦夫饼早就吃完了
Since we're out of waffles, I don't see how that's possible.
那是个奇迹
It's a miracle.
带了手套没？
Gloves?
亨利！
Henry!
快点
Come on.
上车
Get in.
坐好了？
Got it?
因此实际上没人能确定他们身处何地…
So no one's even sure exactly where they are­
…因为那里没有边界没有地标或其它什么标记
­because there's no borders or landmarks or anything.
至于城镇么？那根本算不上什么城镇
And the town? It's not even a town really.
那只不过是个大家聚在一起藏起来的小营地
It just is this camp where all these people have gathered to hide.
好
Right.
所有这些逃兵和被军队赶出来的人
All these deserters and guys that got cut off from their armies.
所有这些人都躲在森林里，努力活下去
All these people that are hiding in the woods, trying to stay alive.
这就是他们归宿
This is where they all came.
那里有盗贼、黑魔导士、佣兵…
There's Thieves, Gray Mages, Unbidden Warriors­
…暗禽、河童、还有穴居魔
­Dark Avians, Riverwynders and Sappers.
-像这样的角色一共有15种，明白么？ -明白
-There's, like, 15 different characters, okay? -Okay.
谁都没有盟友
And nobody has any alliances.
你甚至不能告诉别人你是谁，因为你不知道…
You can't even say who you are because, you don't know­
现在和你说话的这个人…
­maybe the person you're talking to­
会不会就是你战场上的宿敌
­maybe they're like your mortal enemy in the wars.
所以那里的每个人都只能自顾自
So it's just completely like everybody for themselves.
听起来好耳熟啊
Sounds familiar.
真的很棒，真的，你该读读
It's really good. I'm serious, you should really read it.
好的，不过我看完了以后估计你就会迷上了什么别的玩意儿
Right. But by the time I finish it, you'll be on to something else.
-你敢和我打赌吗？ -不知道，你想赌多少？
-How much you wanna bet? -I don't know. How much you got?
-乘车卡带了么？ -放储物柜里了
-You got your bus pass? -It's in my locker.
你根本就不打算看它，对吗？
You're not even gonna look at it, are you?
-那本书吗？ -是的
-The book? -Yes.
星期六把它带来，我会…
Bring it on Saturday, I'll­
我早就带了，放在你厨房里了，红色封面的
I did already. I left it in your kitchen. It's got a red cover.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，到了
Well, here we go.
去吧，好好教教那些人，知道么？
Go. Teach these people something, would you?
-回见，爸爸 -好的，孩子
-See you later, Dad -Yeah, kiddo.
谢谢
Thanks.
第52号拍品，各种各样的搅拌碗，什么型号都有
Lot 52, lot of assorted mixing bowls, assorted sizes.
30美元起，30美元，有人出30美元了
Thirty dollars to start. Thirty dollars. Thirty dollars I have.
你可以出价40，40了，50，后面有人出60了
You can get me to 40. I got 40. And 50. Sixty dollars back there.
现在60，有人出70吗？70了
Sixty dollars, get me to 70. I got 70 dollars.
70美元，现在70了，那里有人出80
Seventy dollars, I have now, 70. Eighty dollars there.
80，这位先生出80，80美元
Eighty dollars, this gentleman here. Eighty dollars.
90美元了，还有人出100吗？100了
Ninety dollars there. Give me 100. One hundred I have now.
他跟我说你还差点儿
He says you're still gonna be short.
差多少？
How short?
6万块，加上扣点，7万5
Sixty. Plus the points, 75 thousand.
-那就是酒和其他东西的价钱？ -你觉得该是多少？
-That's liquor and everything? -What'd you think it was gonna be?
我不知道，可能更少，三两万吧
I don't know. Less. Thirty. Twenty.
他用了1500块买就买走了我那四千块的冰箱
He took 1500 on a refrigerator I paid four grand for.
你开个价
Make a bid.
你不会告诉我说你连7万5都没有吧？
Are you telling me you don't have the 75 thousand?
说真的，没有
Just lying around, no.
我们都知道这事实际上我该找你弟弟谈
We both know it's your brother I should be talking to.
算了吧
Forget that.
迈克尔，你看，你要帮他收拾残局，这是你自己选的
Michael, look, you wanna front this, that's up to you.
但是债务还清之前，提米依然是欠款人
But Timmy's name stays in the book till we're clear.
如果我知道他在哪儿，我就没必要这么一直问下去了
If I know where he is, I don't have to keep asking.
他呆在远郊，他老婆把他领回来了，但我不知道他在哪儿
He's upstate. His wife took him back. I don't know where he is.
他肯定还有点儿值钱的
He's gotta have something.
他就剩老婆和两个孩子了
He's got the two kids with her.
他还有珍妮弗，那被他把肚子搞大的可乐促销员
He's got Jennifer, the coke-dealing waitress that he knocked up.
他还有4个从我妹妹车库里偷走的米其林轮胎
He's got four Michelin radials that he stole from my sister's garage.
你出个价吧
Make an offer.
我曾有个酒鬼老婆，她既年轻又漂亮
I had a wife who was a drunk. She was a beautiful girl, young girl.
但就那样生活？后来有个戒酒计划，她参加了，戒了… 2年
But live like that? Even they do a program­ She did, I think, once, two years.
后来计划没有了呢？别提了
And then they slip? Forget it.
就像你身上捆着个炸弹
It's like you're strapped to a bomb.
我还有多少时间？
What's my timeframe here?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想那不是个问题
I didn't think it'd be a problem.
我会问问的
I'll ask.
-早啊，迈克尔 -早，卡尔
-Hey, Michael -Morning, Carl.
(肯纳、巴赫和莱迪恩律师事务所)
我不知道，戴尔，我不知道你想让我施压到什么程度
I don't know. Del, I don't know how hard you want me to press here.
让我知道他有多大能耐
Let me know how brave he wants to be.
好吧，我现在还不知道他能有多能耐
Well, I'm not sure how brave he can be right now.
我们只是刚刚确认了听证会的时间表
We just got a confirmation hearing scheduled.
她有可能知道吗？
Any chance she knows that?
喔，都上报了，谁知道呢？可能有人读给她听吧
Well, it was in the paper. Who knows? Maybe she got someone to read it to her.
她昨天给他老婆打电话了，打到他家里
She called his wife yesterday. She's calling his house.
这可糟透了
This is a total nightmare.
是的，我猜她无非是想要那套房子
Well, my guess is she's gonna want the condo.
不是吧，那也太疯狂了
Come on, that's insane.
好吧，我还能和你说什么呢？别和算计好了的婊子斗
Well, what can I tell you? Don't piss off a motivated stripper.
简直难以置信
It's just unbelievable.
嗯，这样吧，了解他的底限，然后告诉我
All right. Well, find out his pain threshold and get back to me.
或者你要他直接打电话给我
Or you can tell him to call me directly.
好的，听你的，我来搞定
All right, I hear you. Let me get into it.
好的，就这样，谢谢
Thanks.
嘿，马蒂现在在哪儿？
Hey, where are we with Marty?
我们给他留言了
We left word.
等一下，再说一次，孩子有多大了？
Hold on. Go back. How old is the kid?
他不是“孩子”了，都22了
He's not a kid. He's 22.
-是在迈阿密吗？ -不是，比斯坎湾
-This is Miami? -Nope. Key Biscayne.
他们指控他…
And they charged him.
说他过失伤人，我的委托人…
Reckless endangerment. My client­
我想他们实际上是想要… 想要调查那名律师
I think really what they want, they want a reality check on the attorney down there.
-好吧 -韦恩说你有些门路？
-Yeah -Wayne said you have some connections?
-好的，让我拿支笔 -谢谢
-Yeah, let me get a pen -Thank you.
现在，如果她直接给移民局打电话，那她就哪儿也去不了了
Now, if she calls the INS directly, she's gonna get nowhere.
预约都不行么？
Even with the appointment?
移民局是这么说的，埃文，就像被交通管制了一样
It's retail, Evan. It's like the DMV over there.
除非能得到地区主管的同意，否则没人能离开
Unless they get a call from a district supervisor, then nobody moves.
但你的人不是可以吗？
But your guy can do that?
他已经离任了
He's a former commissioner.
那么现在没人能帮我了？因为干什么都没用了
None of this comes back to me? Because that doesn't do any good.
不，不是，我就是你唯一能够咨询的人
No, look, I'm gonna be the one that's asking.
-你能等两分钟吗？ -当然可以
-Can you hang on a minute? -Yeah, sure.
我们要正在进行合并吗？
Are we merging?
马蒂·巴赫在伦敦
Marty Bach's in London.
起初是说他在亚特兰大，然后娜拉说他就在这栋楼里
They said he was in Atlanta, then Lara said he was in the building.
所以我就给他打了过去，我知道你想和他见面
So I called back. I know you want this meeting.
现在，她告诉我实情了，他确实在伦敦
Now she tells me the truth. He's really in London.
那我们的确是在进行合并了？我是说，大家都在这么说
So are we merging? I mean, that's what everyone's saying.
那些英国佬？这次是来真的了
All these Brits? That this time it's for real.
好像我知道似的
Like I would know.
我不知道
I don't know.
但就算是真的，我是说，就算是合并了，对我们也没多大的影响，对吧？
But even if we are, I mean, even if they merged, it wouldn't affect us, right?
有电话里来了
Your phone's ringing.
埃文？
Evan?
嘿，好的，我打算这么办
Hey. Okay, here's what I'll do.
我给他打个电话下周安排一次会面
Let me give him a call and set up a meeting for next week.
我会把她带来，介绍一下…
I'll walk her in, I'll make the introduction­
目前，U/North公司拥有7万名员工…
At the moment, U/North currently has 70,000 employees­
…分布在全世界62个国家
­  in 62 countries around the world.
覆盖全球
Around the planet.
运作在62个国家，覆盖全球
Operating in 62 countries around the planet.
在世界范围内进驻到60多个国家
At work in more than 60 countries around the globe.
我们拥有… 我们现在拥有… 我们拥有…
We have­  We have, right now­ We have­
U/North公司目前拥有7万5千名员工
At U/North right now, we've got 75,000 employees­
分布在全球60余个国家
­in over 60 countries around the planet.
我们是一个非常成功的多元化的公司
We are a very successful and highly diversified company­
因此你可以想像…
­so you can imagine­
…我们每天要面对大量不同种类的法律问题
­the volume and the variety of legal issues we have to deal with is­
数量巨大的
Overwhelming.
实在是太多了
It's just enormous.
因此你可以想像法律问题的…
So you can imagine, the volume of legal issues­
数量是十分巨大的
It's quite substantial.
作为法律总顾问，我所要做的…
And as general counsel, what I do­
我们内部部门要做的…
­what our in-house department does­
…就是分析问题的大小或者看准时机
­is to analyze the dimension of the problem or the opportunity­
来提出仲裁…
­to determine the jurisdiction­
把我们的业务外包给…
­and to outsource our business­
…那些我们认为对公司最有帮助的企业和个人
­to those firms and talents that we think can help us the most.
那么面对这么大的压力和工作量…
So with all that pressure and workload­
…你是如何在工作和生活之间平衡的呢？
­  how do you keep a balance between work and life?
平衡？
Balance?
我想… 有些东西…
I think that's­  That's something that­
…你会耗尽毕生精力去探寻的，对吗？
­you search for your whole life, isn't it?
实际上，那是一种变换着的平衡
It's a shifting balance, really.
这是，你知道，你… 你试着去…
It's, you know, you­  You try to­
当你真的喜欢你的事业时…
When you really are enjoying what it is you do­
…谁还会在乎什么平衡呢？
­who needs balance?
这就是你的平衡，这就是你的平衡
There's your balance. There's your balance.
当你真的喜欢你的事业时，那就是你的平衡所在
When you're really enjoying what it is you do, there is your balance.
当丹要我担任…
When Don asked me to take­
当丹·杰弗瑞带上… 丹·杰弗瑞带我…
When Don Jeffries brought­ Don Jeffries brought me­
12年前丹·杰瑞弗把我带到这儿来…
Don Jeffries brought me in here 12 years ago­
…给予我信任，悉心指导我
­trusted me, mentored me.
欢迎我加入U/North这个大家庭
Welcomed me into the U/North family.
当他升到董事会后，我做梦都没…
And when he moved up to the boardroom, I never really­
…没想过我会有机会坐到他的位置上
­dreamt that I would have the opportunity to move into his position.
但，这是不是很有挑战性？当然
But, is it challenging? Yes.
我想在最初的几个月里的确有点磕磕绊绊
And I think that it's possible that those first few months were a little shaky.
但当你意识到你所学的让你有备而来，你就会把握住方向
But then you realize that you've been taught to be ready, and you take the helm.
因为如果你没有准备好承担相应的责任…
Because if you're not comfortable with that level of responsibility­
…那你就不适合坐这个位置
­you're in the wrong place.
这是你的部门，你有能力在关键时刻做出决定…
It's your department, your capacity to make tough decisions in real time, and­
我们正在录节目
We're in the middle of an interview.
他们说这是紧急情况
They said it was urgent.
老天
Jesus.
上帝啊
For chrissake.
你是说他这么做了，在…？
You're saying he did this in­?
噢，天啊
Oh, my God.
-巴里 -等一下
-Barry -Hang on.
亚瑟·伊顿刚刚在密尔沃基的证人室里脱了个精光
Arthur Edens just stripped down naked in a deposition room in Milwaukee.
哦，迈克尔…
Oh, Michael­
…我深深地、彻底地吸了口气，把我那想法放到一边，我放下了它
­  I took a deep, cleansing breath and I set that notion aside. I tabled it.
我对自已说：很显然，这种强烈的感觉…
I said to myself, "As clear as this may be, as potent a feeling as this is­
…和我今天见证的东西一样真实，但它需要等待
­  as true a thing as I believe that I have witnessed today, it must wait.
它必须经受住时间的考验
It must stand the test of time. "
现在，迈克尔，时候到了
And, Michael, the time is now.
就此时、今天、这里、这房子、这空气…
This moment, today, here, this room, this air­
…还有这点，特别是这点，迈克尔，你也来了
­  and this, especially this, Michael, that you're here.
这就是原因
There's a reason.
你就是一个原因，迈克尔
A reason it's you, Michael.
当然，你会对它有些感觉，它是如何拼凑，又是如何聚集的
Surely, you have some sense of that, how it pulls together, how it gathers.
看门人迈克尔，幕后英雄，隐藏罪恶的守护者
Nurse Michael, the secret hero, the keeper of the hidden sins.
看在上帝份上，迈克尔，告诉我这你都明白
Tell me you can see that, Michael, for God's sake.
但是，我要说，是的… 裸体，在停车场，我承认
But, I mean, yeah, yes, yes. The nudity, the parking lot, I admit it.
那是… 那是… 是个错误，那很无聊、很软弱
It was­  It was­  It was a mistake. It was wrong. It was lame.
很明显的，那些药剂根本就不起作用…
It was obvious. And therapeutically, it was completely useless­
但我发誓，我会在这里不要这老脸…
­because I swear, I could stand here and tear off my fucking skin­
…就是因为不能忍受那些鬼东西存在
­and I could not get down to where this thing is living.
6年了，迈克尔，6年来我一直在吸收这些毒素
Six years, Michael. Six years I've absorbed this poison.
400多人作证，100多人提出动议，5次改变审判地点…
Four hundred depositions, a hundred motions, five changes of venue­
…8万5千份卷宗
­85,000 documents in discovery.
6年来不停地谋划、拖延与惊恐，我又得到了什么？
Six years of scheming and stalling and screaming, and what have I got?
耗费了我12%生命来维护这该死的除草剂公司的声誉！
I've spent 12 percent of my life defending the reputation of a deadly weed killer!
-我们说好了的，亚瑟 -有天晚上
-We had an agreement, Arthur -One night.
有天晚上，知道吧？我发现马蒂在我的办公室里
One night, right? I look up and there's Marty in my office.
拿着香槟酒
He's got some champagne.
他说我们已经为U/North提供了3万小时的收费服务，他想庆祝一下
He tells me we just hit 30,000 billable hours on U/North and he wants to celebrate.
一小时后，我发现自己在切尔西区的一家妓院里…
So an hour later, I find myself in a whorehouse in Chelsea­
…两个红发的立陶宛女人在我下身轮流给我吹喇叭
­with two Lithuanian redheads taking turns sucking my dick.
我躺在那里，想多爽一会儿，我想…
I'm laying there and I'm trying not to come and I wanna­
我想多“挺”一会儿，所以我就开始计算别的
I wanna make it last, so I start doing the math.
我想3万小时，那是多久呀，24乘以30
I think, "Thirty thousand hours, what is that? That's 24 times 30.
一个月是720小时，一年是8760小时…
That's 720 hours in a month, 8760 hours in a year­"
-亚瑟 -不，等等，等等，听我说！
-Arthur -No, wait, wait, wait!
那是多少年呀！那可是多少条命啊！
Because it's years! It's lives!
这些数字让我发晕，你知道…
And the numbers are making me dizzy and, you know­
…现在，我不再考虑怎么多“挺”一会儿了，我开始试着不要再思考下去，但我停不下来
­now, instead of trying not to come, I'm trying not to think, and I can't stop.
我想，这是我吗？
I mean, is this me?
我是个被送到这里来吃喝玩乐…
Am I this freak organism that has been sent here to sleep and eat­
…然后为那个让人毛骨悚然的致癌链式分子做辩护的大傻瓜么？
­and defend this one horrific chain of carcinogenic molecules?
难道这就是我的命运？我的定数？
Is that my destiny? Is that my fate?
-听着，你答应过我 -是吗，迈克尔？
-Listen, you promised me -Is that it, Michael?
这就是我长期努力的目标？两个立陶宛娘们儿给我吹喇叭？
Is that my grail? Two Lithuanian mouths on my cock?
这就是我的多项选择的正确答案吗？
Is that the correct answer to the multiple choice of me?
你想不吃药，也可以，但你得先给我打电话
You wanna go off your medication, that's fine. But you call me first.
-那是我们约好的 -告我去啊
-That was our agreement -Sue me.
你们俩没事吧？
We okay in there?
我们俩没事，没事
We're fine. We're fine.
除草剂杀死了他们，迈克尔
They killed them, Michael.
那些小农庄，家族农场
Those small farms, the family farms.
你有… 你有… 你有见过安娜吗？
Did you­? Did you­? Did you meet Anna?
没有
No.
你得去看看她，你得去找她谈谈，她很了不起，迈克尔
You gotta see her, you gotta talk to her. She's a miracle, Michael.
她可是造物主创造的最完美的小精灵
She's God's perfect little creature.
为了那5千万美元的费用，我花去了12%的生命…
And for 50 million dollars in fees, I've spent 12 percent of my life­
…毁掉了完美的安娜，还有她那已故的父母和奄奄一息的哥哥
­destroying perfect Anna and her dead parents and her dying brother.
你最后一次吃这些是什么时候？
When did you last take one of these?
不，这玩意儿我还有，这一切都是有原因的
No. I'm not losing this. Everything is finally significant.
这是个美好的世界，我什么都不想换了
The world is a beautiful place. I'm not trading that.
-即使一切都是真的，这药也不会害了你 -我手上沾满了鲜血
-If it's real, the pill won't kill it -I have blood on my hands.
你是全球最大、最知名律师事务所的
You are senior litigating partner of one of the largest­
资深合伙人，你是个传奇人物
­most respected law firms in the world. You are a legend.
-我只是个帮凶！ -你只不过是有躁狂抑郁症
-I'm an accomplice! -You're a manic-depressive.
我是湿婆(印度教的主神之一，世界的毁灭者和重建者，死亡之神)
I am Shiva, the god of death.
让我们离开密尔沃基吧，以后再说这个
Let's get out of Milwaukee, we'll talk about it.
我们从医院回来之后，大家都哭了…
We came back from the hospital and everybody was crying­
…我们当时很惊讶，但我们还得… 我们不得不去挤奶
­  and we were in shock, but we still­ We had to milk.
奶牛可不会等你，是吧？
The cows won't wait, will they?
不会
No.
当你们来到牛棚时？
And when you went to the barn?
我们发现了一个便条，我妹妹找到的
We found the note. My sister found it.
-你母亲留的？ -是的
-From your mother? -Yes.
你能给我们读一下么？
Could you read it for us, please?
就读第三段吧，就读那些标记过的地方
Just read the third paragraph, just the highlighted section there.
“我不想你责怪奈德·哈迪或者其他人…”
"I don't want you blaming Ned Hardy or any of the people­  "
安娜
Anna.
-安娜 -在…
-Anna -"Down at­
没事儿，安娜，继续
It's all right, Anna, go on.
-我只是… -不好意思
-I'm just­ -Excuse me.
-安娜，他们… -他在做什么呀？
-Anna, they're­ -What's he doing?
对不起，她是… 不，这是在作证，这是…
Excuse me. She's a­ No, this is testimony. This is­
对不起，我反对
Excuse me, I have an objection.
你可以在这儿做个证人，你可以做个证人
You can be a witness here. You can be a witness.
我不是证人，先生，我…
I am not a witness to this, sir, l­
安娜，我爱你
Anna, I love you.
我坐在这儿，认真听你说，我发誓…
And I'm sitting here and I'm listening to you and I swear­
…我爱你胜过这世上的一切，这是属于我的时刻
­  that I love you more than anything in the world. And this is my moment.
这诡异的会议时刻
This strange conference-table moment.
快把摄像机关了！
Turn off that camera!
-这是我的表白！ -别关，把这些录下来！
-This is my offering! -No, I want this on the record!
我到底关不关？
How do I turn it off?
这就是我的供词，我的衣服就是供词，这就是我的耻辱
This is my offering. My clothes are my offering. This is my shame.
我的资格！我被污辱了！
My credentials! I'm ashamed!
我爱你，我向上帝发誓…
And I love you, and I swear to God­
我想就这些
I guess that's it.
我们什么时候能见到丹？
When do we get Don?
她说争取半小时之内回来
She said to try back in half an hour.
航班情况呢？机场情况怎么样？
And how about the flights? What's the story at O'Hare?
-四分钟前关闭了 -该死
-Closed four minutes ago -Shit.
底特律的积雪已经有一英尺厚了
There is a foot of snow in Detroit already.
托德，能给我来杯咖啡吗？
Todd, could I get that coffee now?
他们从纽约派过来的是谁？克莱顿？没听说过
Who is this guy they sent from New York? Clayton? I never heard of him.
Who is this guy they sent from New York? Clayton?
I never heard of him.
迈克尔·雷蒙德·克莱顿
Michael Raymond Clayton.
生于1959年9月9号，纽约布朗克斯区圣约瑟夫医院
Born September 9, 1959, St. Joseph's Hospital, Bronx, New York.
父亲雷蒙德·沙维尔·克莱顿是纽约警局的巡警
Father is NYPD patrolman Raymond Xavier Clayton.
母亲爱丽丝·玛丽·克莱顿
Mother, Alice Mary Clayton.
1977年毕业于纽约奥伦奇郡的…
Graduates Washingtonville Central High School, Orange County, New York­
…华盛顿中央高中
­  in 1977.
1980年毕业于圣·约翰大学，82年福特汉姆法学院毕业
Graduates St. John's University, 1980. Fordham Law, '82.
82到86年，在皇后区司法部门担任助理检察官
'82 through '86, he's ADA with the Queens district attorney's office.
1986年，他加入了曼哈顿—皇后区…
…有组织犯罪特别小组
­  Organized Crime Task Force.
1990年，他开始在肯纳、巴赫和莱迪恩律师事务所工作
And then in 1990, he starts at Kenner, Bach & Ledeen.
那么他是合伙人喽？
So he's a partner?
不，他被列为特约顾问
No. He's listed as special counsel.
上面写了他的专长是遗产法和信托法
Says he specializes in wills and trusts.
他从刑事诉讼转型到遗产法和信托法？
He goes from criminal prosecution to wills and trusts?
他在那里干了17年了，还不是合伙人？
He's been there 17 years, he's not a partner?
这就是他们派来的人？这家伙到底是谁？
This is the guy they send? Who is this guy?
-你好 -把门关好
-Hi -Close the door.
好，你们当中没有人知道他来了吧？
All right. So nobody, none of you, had any idea he was coming?
去密尔沃基？去听证会？
To Milwaukee? For a deposition?
我们以为已经解决了，有一些传言，所以我们觉得事情已经妥了
We thought there was a settlement. There's been some rumors.
是这样，这事非常简单，亚瑟没有按量服药
Okay. Look, it's very simple. Arthur has a chemical imbalance.
他应该坚持吃药，但他没有
He's supposed to be taking his medication. He's fallen behind on that.
现在他正在好转中，三四天后他就会好的
He's on the mend. He'll be fine in three or four days.
现在，我给你们说清楚，这屋子里发生的一切都不要透露出去
Now, I wanna make this crystal clear. What happened here stays in this room.
一点一滴信息都不能泄露
This is not a piece of information you wanna be out in front of.
还有人有问题吗，有就马上说
Anybody has a problem with that, I need to know right now.
很好
All right.
我们今晚就得在这儿过了
We're stuck here overnight.
如果可能的话我明天就送他回家
I'm gonna take him home tomorrow if I can.
谁负责听证会的时间表？
Who's in charge of the deposition schedule?
-我 -我们现在进行到什么程度了？
-I am -Where do we stand with that?
我想我们可能停住了，我们不知道下一步该做些什么
I guess it's on hold. We didn't know what to do.
没有停下来的事，你继续做你们该做的
Nothing is on hold. Keep doing what you were.
对方想谈些什么的话，他们可以纽约打电话
Other side wants to talk, they can call New York.
-我要他的公文包 -亚瑟的？不知道… 没看见
-I need his briefcase -Arthur's? I don't­  I didn't see it.
-他说就在房间里 -可能朱迪拿走了吧
-He said it was in the room -It might be the stuff Jody grabbed.
找到它
Find it.
所有这些人，都开始有这些梦了，对吧？
So all these people, they all start having these dreams, okay?
你知道什么叫“幻象探索”么？嗯，就像那些纳瓦霍人(美洲印第安人的一支)那样
You know what a vision quest is? You know, for, like, Navajos and stuff?
嗯，我知道，就像…
Yeah. I think so. Like a­
就像一个特别的梦
Like a special dream.
不同之处就在于所有人都做一样的梦
Except this is like a whole bunch of people having the same dream.
这个梦让他们大家都到同一个地方
They're all having this dream that they should go to this one place.
他们不知道为什么要这样做
They don't know why or anything.
但他们就是有种非去那里不可的感觉
They just have this feeling that they have to go there.
他们是召唤的一群人
That they've been summoned.
那就是其中的一章
That's the chapter.
真的，就叫做“召唤与征服”
Seriously, that's what it's called: "Summons to Conquest."
这是标题
That's the title.
嗯，但他们知道么？他们知道他们的梦都一样吗？
Yeah, but do they know? Do they know they're all having the same dream?
不知道，这就是精彩的地方
No. That's what's so cool.
他们都觉得只有自己才有
They all think it's just them.
也许他们可能已经疯了，但他们就是不想承认
That maybe they're, like, going crazy or something, so they don't wanna admit it.
是呀，但其实他们没有发疯，对吗？
Yeah, but they're not crazy, are they?
不，一切都是真的，他们没有疯
No. It's real. It's really happening.
是的，都是真的，不是么？
Yeah, it is happening, isn't it?
有东西比他们更为强大，而他们还没有准备好…
Something larger than themselves and they're not ready, are they­
…他们会察觉到么？
­to hear it?
是的，不久之后他们就会
Yeah. But later they will.
如果你想看这本书的话，我就不再透露情节了
So if you're gonna read it, I don't wanna spoil it.
你在干什么，和谁说话呢？
What are you doing? Who you talking to?
我给我爸爸打电话，他的一个朋友接的
I called my dad. It's a friend of his.
-谁？ -伊顿先生，你不认识他
-Who? -Mr.Edens. You don't know him.
-喂，喂 -亨利，已经11点多了
-Hello? Hello? -Henry, it's after 11.
我得马上挂了
I gotta get off now.
不，等下，那本书，我想看看，书名是什么
No. Wait, wait. The book. I need the book. The title.
书名是《王国与征服》
The book is Realm and Conquest.
《王国与征服》
Realm and Conquest.
-单行本，红色封面的 -亨利，把电话给我
-It's Book One, with the red cover -Henry, give me the phone.
我得挂了，告诉我爸我给他打电话了，好吗？
I gotta go. Tell my dad I called. Okay?
好，好的，谢… 谢，谢谢你，亨利，谢谢你
Yeah. Yeah. Thank­  Thank­  Thank­ Thank you, Henry, thank you.
《王国与征服》，谢谢
Realm and Conquest. Thank you.
凯伦？你好，我是迈克尔·克莱顿
Karen? Hi, I'm Michael Clayton.
-你迟到了 -我知道
-You're late -I know.
对不起，这事比我们预想的要复杂
I'm sorry, it was more complicated than we thought.
他在哪儿？五点半我们就在这儿了
Where is he? We've been here since 5:30.
-他睡了 -那么，把他叫起来
-He's asleep -Well, wake him up.
那可不行，我们刚让他安静下来
That's not gonna happen. We just got him sedated.
只要他接受日常的药物治疗…
Once he gets back on his regular medication­
…不多时间他就能回来
­then it's just a matter of time.
-你有看那段录像么？那盘带子？ -我听说了
-Have you seen the video? The tape? -I heard about it.
那之后发生的事情更糟
What happened after is worse.
那可是停车场，人们停车开车的地方
This is in the parking lot, okay? People running for their cars.
他在那里就穿了双袜子，别的没了
He's there in his socks, nothing else.
对不起，很抱歉，我再也不想和这疾病为伍了
"I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I will not sit with this sickness any longer.
我再也不能助长这疾病了
I cannot aid this sickness any longer."
这话什么意思？
What does this mean?
我也不清楚
I'm not sure.
你整晚和他在一起，他说了些什么？
You've been with him the whole evening. What's he saying?
他没说什么有用的
He wasn't really making much sense.
你这解释我可不能接受
This is totally unacceptable.
这可是价值30亿美元的集体诉讼
This is a 3-billion-dollar class-action lawsuit.
到了早上，我不得不给我老板汇报
In the morning, I have to call my board.
告诉他们我们这案子的首席辩护律师被逮逋了
I have to tell them that the architect of our entire defense has been arrested­
…因为他在暴风雪中裸奔，并在停车场追赶原告
­for running naked in a snowstorm, chasing the plaintiffs through a parking lot.
我能理解
I understand.
他说的那疾病到底是什么？
What sickness is he talking about?
-不知道，可能是什么别的东西 -那好，是什么？
-I don't know. It could be anything -Well, give me one.
冻伤吧
Frostbite.
你觉得这很好玩吗？
You think this is funny?
你看，他的妻子病了，去年去世的
Look, his wife was sick and she died last year.
他的女儿不理他了，他很孤独，他现在的生活就只有你的案子
His daughter doesn't talk to him. He's all alone. All he does is your case.
他忘了吃药，度过了糟糕的一天，仅此而已
He skipped his pills. He had a bad day. That's it.
看来你是这方面的权威喽？
And you're somehow the authority on this?
他上次发病是在八年前，当时我在场
His last episode was eight years ago. I was there.
我帮他回到家，看着他好转，就这样
I helped bring him home. I watched him get better. That's it.
行了，凯伦，你雇佣他不是因为他有抑郁证
Come on, Karen, you didn't hire this guy because of his low-key regularity­
你雇他是因为他是最棒的，因为他的才智…
­you hired him because he's a killer, because he's brilliant­
因为他在这个案子上足够执着努力…
­because he's crazy enough to grind away on this case­
-…6年来无休止地工作着 -打断一下，我们可是给了他工钱的
­for six years without a break -We pay for his time.
我知道你想要个解释
I thought you wanted an explanation.
到了早上，我会给马蒂·巴赫打电话的
In the morning, I'm calling Marty Bach.
然后么，你也知道的，谢谢你，迈克尔
But, then, you know that. Thank you, Michael.
他大部份时候很平静
He was mostly just quiet.
我听到他的动静，15分钟前我给他吃了药
I heard him moving around, I gave him a pill 15 minutes ago.
-他吃了？ -说到做到，对吧？
-He took it? -A deaI's a deal, right?
干的不错，埃尔森
A super job, Elston.
你去纽约吧，如果需要入场券或其它什么东西和我说就行
You get to New York, you need tickets to the game or anything, you let me know.
我会把这事办好的
I'll do that for sure.
你见过她了吗？
Did you see her?
-谁？ -安娜
-Who? -Anna.
没有
No.
没有，我没见到她，她可能回农场了
No, I didn't see her. She probably went back to the farm.
嗯，我们需要她
Well, we need her.
马蒂，还有其他的几个人，他们不会明白的
Marty, even then, and the rest of them, they won't understand.
那么如果有人能够给他们解释的话，那人就是你了，亚瑟
Well, if anybody can explain it to them, it's you, Arthur.
不，他们已经迷失方向了
No, they're lost.
-他们已经得到他们想要的了 -别想了，伙计
-They have what they want -Let it go, man.
这就是你想要的？
This what you wanted?
当个看门的？
To be a janitor?
像这样生活下去？就这样？
Live like this? All this?
做你该做的？
Do what you do?
不可能的
It can't be.
那是…
It's­
那是种负担，这就是我一直想告诉你的
It's a burden, that's what I'm trying to tell you.
就是… 就是这种感觉
That's­  That's how it feels.
我知道我们是被召唤的
Well, I know that we've been summoned.
早点睡吧
Get some sleep.
喂
Hello?
你好，我想找韦恩？
Yes. Hi, I'm looking for Verne?
你有号码吗？
You have a number?
丹·杰弗瑞给的我这个号码，他说我什么时间打都行
Don Jeffries gave me the number. He said I could call at any time.
不，我是指帐号
No. The account number.
帐号？我有，等一下，我看看
The code? I do. I have it right here. One moment.
稍等片刻
Excuse me one moment.
找到了，12-BKR-6
It's right here. 12-BKR-6.
-BKR-6
你是韦恩吗？
Am I speaking with Verne?
是的，我是
It's Mr.Verne.
韦恩先生，不好意思，这么晚打扰你
Mr.Verne. I'm sorry, it's so late.
丹说我可以…
Don said that I could­
我不是很清楚这东西的用法
I'm not exactly sure how this works.
你现在能上网收电子邮件吗？
Do you have e-mail at your current location?
我有
I do.
-你现在一个人吗？ -是的
-Are you alone? -I am.
这样，我会给你上传一个我们常用的小加密包
Okay, I'm gonna upload you a little encryption package we like to use.
那上面写的很清楚
It's pretty self-explanatory.
-好的 -好
-Okay -Okay.
不过你得等几分钟，我得到办公桌那里去，别挂
But you have to give me a minute to get to my desk. Hold on.
好的，谢谢你
Okay. Thank you.
(内部使用) (北地联合克林泰特除草剂内部研究备忘录229号)
(229号内部研究备忘录)
(清楚所有已上市的克林泰特…)
(…能够对人体组织造成伤害…)
(无色、无味… 潜在的致命威胁)
我想知道的是…
What I was wondering is­
…我是不是有续租六年的优先选择权
­I have an option on the lease for six more years.
我在想有没有办法可解除那种情况
I was wondering if there's any way I could lay that off.
这租约还有价值么？
Is the lease worth anything?
8万9一个月，那…
Eighty-nine hundred a month. It's­
没有装修，但有…
The fixtures are gone, but there's­
但还有吧台，还有厨房，那地方不错
But there's the bar, there's a kitchen, it's a great space.
可是还有…
But there's a­
好，我明白了，不，我明白了
Yeah, I understand. No, I understand.
好的，好，我会的
Okay, yeah, I will.
好，谢了
All right. Thanks.
好了，亚瑟
Come on, Arthur.
亚瑟！
Arthur!
亚瑟，开门
Arthur, open the door.
亚瑟，快开门！
Arthur, open the door!
亚瑟，快他妈的把门打开！
Arthur, open the goddamn door!
亚瑟，开…！
Arthur, op­!
快他娘的开门！
Open the fucking door!
亚瑟！
Arthur!
该死的，亚瑟！快他妈的…！
Goddamn it, Arthur! Open the fucking­!
亚瑟？！
Arthur?!
(相信吧，这绝不只是疯狂)
-韦恩先生么，你好 -你好，丹尼
-Mr.Verne, hey -Hey, Danny.
你的人来早了，我还在收拾其他的包
You guys are early. I was pulling the other bags.
你可以把它们放在后面，计划有变，抱歉
You can put them back. There's been a change of plans, sorry.
-我们准备好了么？ -是的
-We ready? -Yep.
天啊
For chrissake.
丹·杰弗瑞签署的？
Don Jeffries signed this?
这真是他的签名？
That's really his signature?
正本在哪儿？
Where's the original?
5年前库房失火了，我们损失了很多档案
We had a warehouse fire five years ago. We lost a number of documents.
这玩意儿怎么会在亚瑟的包里？
What the hell is this doing in Arthur's bag?
那个，我也不知道，马蒂
Well, I don't know, Marty.
我还希望你能告诉我些事情呢
That's something I was hoping you might be able to tell me.
我们要找什么？
What are we looking for?
如果提到了U/North公司，就放在一边，任何提到U/North的材料
If it says U/North, pull it aside. Anything that says U/North.
这儿真是一团糟
What a mess this is.
我这儿所有的…
I want all this­
…所有的东西，打包后送到办公室去
­everything here, I want it all packed up and sent up to the house.
一切还好么，迈克尔？
Any luck, Michael?
他3点在纽华克机场上了辆出租，在西四大街下了车…
He booked a limo from Newark Airport at 3, got out at West Fourth Street­
…给了司机一张百元大钞当小费，走掉了
­tipped the driver 100 bucks and walked away.
你去过他的公寓了么？
Did you try his apartment?
-他搬家了 -我知道
-He moved -I know.
那是间阁楼，没有门卫，我按了门铃，没人
It's a loft. No doorman. I rang, nobody answered.
-我打电话，他开了答录机 -那么说他不知去向了
-I called, I got the machine -So he could be anywhere.
亚瑟住在城里不是什么好事，住什么狗屁阁楼
Arthur downtown is not a good idea. Some goddamn loft.
-他女儿在哪儿？ -我不知道，西班牙或者是印度
-Where's his daughter? -I don't know. Spain, India.
马尔斯，比她爸爸还疯狂
Mars. She's crazier than he'll ever be.
巴里接手U/North的事情
Barry's taking over on U/North.
我们又有不少罪要受了
We got a lot of groveling to do.
你可不怎么受凯伦·克劳德的欢迎
You didn't exactly charm Karen Crowder.
我被踢开了
I was punting.
你在这儿做好准备，掌控好局面
You gotta saddle up here and get things under control.
做好什么准备？
Saddle up?
他需要立即接受医生诊断，他需要被允许住院治疗
He needs to be under a doctor's care. He needs to be admitted.
-住哪儿？ -这很重要么？
-Where? -Does that really matter?
迈克尔，U/North想知道他已经被控制住了
Michael, U/North needs to know he's under control.
他要在医院里，他们被吓坏了，他们需要恢复信心
He's in a facility. They've been shook up. They need to be reassured.
-没那么容易的 -为什么没那么容易？
-It's not gonna be that easy -Why the hell not?
因为纽约的法律对于进行非自愿的精神治疗要求很严格
Because the laws in New York are pretty tough on involuntary commitment.
你看了那狗屁录影带了么？
Did you see this fucking tape?
我不和你吵，巴里，我在你说这是怎么回事
I'm not arguing with you, Barry. I'm telling you how it is.
知道么，伙计们？我们这里有600个律师
You know what, guys? We got 600 lawyers in this place.
我们为什么不去找一个更了解精神病强制治疗法的人来呢？
Why don't we find out which one knows about psychiatric-commitment statutes?
我现在就可以告诉你为什么，因为他是亚瑟
I can tell you that right now. It's Arthur.
我在门这儿，准备好进去了
I'm at the door. We're good to go.
好的，收到，每5分钟通话一次，明白么？
Yeah, roger that. Let's keep a radio check every five, okay?
5分钟一次，收到
Every five minutes, copy that.
你好，这里是亚瑟的答录机
Hello, you've reached Arthur's machine.
如果你要留言，请在铃声后开始
If you wish to leave a message, please do so after the tone.
亚瑟，快接电话
Arthur, pick up the phone.
亚瑟，快接电话，和我说话
Arthur, pick up the phone and talk to me.
不干？不打算接？
No? Not gonna do it?
不管昨天早上发生了什么，忘掉它，没关系的
What happened yesterday morning, forget it. It doesn't matter.
总有一天我们会一笑置之的
Someday you and I are gonna laugh about it.
但你一定要给我回电话
But you gotta call me back.
你要快点儿给我回电话，亚瑟
You gotta call me back soon, Arthur.
我告诉你为什么
I'll tell you what.
因为那是你自己说的，这事有些部份确实是很疯狂
Because you said it yourself. Part of this is definitely madness.
还有一部份是化学药品的原因，我们都清楚
And there's a chemical part. We both know it.
如果你打算对此采取某些行动…
But if you're willing to start with that­
我非常愿意去协助你，我会告诉你，是的…
­  then I'm more than willing to meet you halfway and say, yes­
…这情况很糟，这案子也很糟，U/North也不是什么好鸟
­this situation sucks. This case sucks. U/North sucks.
我们可以一起行动，好么，亚瑟？你听到了么？
We can start with that. All right, Arthur? You hear me?
你那时候说的对
You're right about what we are.
我是说你疯了，说你的行为失去了控制
I'm saying you're crazy. I'm saying that your behavior is out of control.
但我要告诉你，你说的对
But I'm telling you you're right.
你说过，我们是看门人，我承认
You called it. We're janitors, I get it.
但我们为此而来，亚瑟
But we came to this, Arthur.
我们一起做过决定，那不是容易的事
We made decisions. It didn't happen overnight.
你不能突然停下来说：“就这样吧，游戏结束了，我进入了神迹”
You can't just suddenly stop and say, "That's it, game over. I'm into miracles."
亚瑟，求求你
Arthur. Come on.
该死的，拿起电话来和我说话
Goddamn it, pick up the phone and talk to me.
因为无论你是怎么想的那都很重要…
Because whatever else you think is so important­
你要让我帮助你，因为我会和你谈…
­you better let me help you, because I'm telling you­
…直来直去的，看门人和看门人之间，你不用孤军奋战
­janitor to janitor, I don't see anybody else with a broom on the horizon.
是我，伙计，我是…
It's me, buddy. I'm the­
收件箱已满，您的信息不能被录制
Mailbox is full. Your message cannot be recorded.
-喂 -喂，安娜在么？
-Hello? -Hello. Is Anna there?
稍等
Hang on.
安娜！
Anna!
她上哪儿去了？安娜！
Where is she? Anna!
-安娜！ -安娜！
-Anna! -Anna!
安娜，有你的电话！
Anna, you've got a phone call!
上哪儿去了？安娜！
Where is she? Anna!
喂
Hello?
安娜，你好，是我，亚瑟
Anna, hi. It's Arthur.
-你好 -你休息得好么？
-Hey -Did you get some sleep?
还行吧
I guess.
你考虑过我们说的事了么？
Did you think about what we said?
-是的 -你没告诉别人，是么？
-Yeah -You didn't tell anybody, did you?
没有，我姐姐在监视我，但那很正常
No. My sister's spying on me, but that's normal.
好，因为我就是那个意思
Yeah. Because I meant what I said.
我知道，我知道，只是…
I know. I know. It's just­
…这件案子里有450个人
­there's, like, 450 people in this lawsuit.
你为什么选中我呢？
Why are you choosing me?
我也不知道，大概是疯了吧？
I don't know. I'm crazy, right?
确实是
That's for sure.
我是说，真的…？那真的有关系么？
I mean, does it­? Does it really matter?
我说，那不是我们所期待的么？遇见某个人？
I mean, isn't it what we wait for? To meet someone? And they're­
他们就像… 就像透镜…
They're like a lens­
你透过他们看世界，突然世界都变了…
­and suddenly you're looking through them and everything changes­
…一切都改变了
­and nothing can ever be the same again.
你跟谁说话呢？
Who you talking to?
找我的，明白吗？也有电话找我的
It's for me, okay? I get calls too.
那个人？
That guy?
还是那个，还是那个
Same guy. Same guy.
抱歉
Sorry.
不，没… 没关系，我妈妈过去也听我打电话
No. That's­  That's okay. My mother used to listen to my calls.
她觉得我什么都做不好
She can't believe I can do anything on my own.
嗯，会改变的
Well, that'll change.
我想也是
I guess.
是的，你看，我们可以给她看些东西
Yeah, but, see, that's something we can show her.
让她知道你能行
That you can do something.
如果你需要，我们可以… 我们可以一起干
That we could­  We could do that together if you want. I mean­
我是说，我是说我可以帮助你
I mean that I can help you do that.
周一我可以搞到1万2
I can get you 12 by Monday.
1万2太少了，不怎么好
Twelve's weak. Twelve looks bad.
什么意思？
How do you figure that?
他们看看7万5，再看看你，他们想知道是哪里出了问题
They look at 75 and they look at you and they wonder what the problem is.
而你就给了1万2，这会让他们很紧张的
You say 12. That's gonna make people nervous.
才过了2天，给我点回旋的余地
This was the day before yesterday. Let me get my ducks in order.
车值多少？
What's the car worth?
租的，是公司的
It's a lease. It's the firm's.
那么？你去银行，把公寓抵押了，再申请贷款
So? You go to the bank. You've got the apartment. You refinance.
不行，三个月前我就那么干过了
I can't. I did that three months ago.
你是不是又赌牌去了？
Are you back at the tables?
看来我得重操旧业了，我没什么闲钱了
Like I need that kind of action. I don't have enough going on.
希望你是在和我说笑呢
I hope you're kidding.
要是他发现你用他的钱玩牌，你就完了
If he finds out you're playing cards with his money, there's no dialogue after that.
行行好吧
Do everyone a favor.
快把你的藏宝图拿出来挖宝吧
Get out the treasure map and start digging.
你有一周的时间
You got a week.
-你好，迈克尔，还好么？ -你好，辛迪，我很好
-Hey, Michael. How are you? -Hi, Cindy. I'm good.
请进，他一早上都在打电话，有什么新消息？
Come in. He's been on the phone all morning. What else is new?
我一直在试着让他离开15分钟
I am trying to get him out in 15 minutes.
-他在楼上么？ -他把所有的起居室都占了
-Is he upstairs? -He's taken over the living room.
你们俩小家伙干啥呢？快下来
What are you guys doing? Get down here.
索罗约，我告诉过你看好孩子，让他们在楼下玩
Soroyo, I told you to keep an eye on these kids, make sure they're downstairs.
马蒂？
Marty?
你知道他在干什么吗？他在帮他们打官司
You know what he's doing? He's making their case.
我看了他的文件，我看了这个…
I'm going through his files here, I'm reading this­
…他在把案子办成针对U/North的
­he's building a case against U/North.
-没人会允许他这么做的 -允许他？
-Nobody's gonna let him do that -Let him?
谁能阻止他？
Who the helI's gonna stop him?
你知道我刚听说了什么吗？他在给原告打电话
You know what I just heard? He's calling these plaintiffs.
比如作证的那个女的，他现在在联系这些人
This woman from the deposition, he's calling these people now.
他拿到的这些卷宗，简直是他妈的噩梦
He's got these discovery documents. This is a fucking nightmare.
我试着联系他，留不了言，他的答录机满了
I tried him. Can't even leave a message. He's got the machine jammed up.
-那是他的公文包么？ -是啊
-Is that his briefcase? -Yeah.
-怎么了？ -我们一直在找它
-Why? -We've been looking for it.
我也不知道，它就和他办公室里的其他破烂一起出现了
I don't know. It came up here with all the other stuff from his office.
你肯定不相信他那儿有多少破烂
You can't believe the crap he's got in here.
我说，马蒂…
Listen, Marty­
…我在这儿欠了点钱
­I'm in a bind here.
我得借点钱，8万块
I need a loan. I need 80 grand.
-我还以为你都解决了呢 -还没有
-I thought you were done with that -It's not that.
不是赌牌欠的，那个不欠了，是餐馆的钱
It's not the cards. It's none of that. It's the restaurant.
8万块
Eighty thousand.
很抱歉突然来打扰你
I'm sorry to jump you like this.
两周来我一直试着和你会面
I've been trying to get a meeting with you for two weeks.
还有不管应不应该，我都知道了合并的事
And I know about the merger, whether I'm supposed to or not.
合并的事还没有定论
There's nothing final on the merger.
嗯，那就是为什么我现在问你，你是我的生活来源
Well, that's why I'm asking you now. You're my meal ticket.
一旦你退出了，就剩我和巴里还有一屋子的陌生人…
Once you're out, it's me and Barry with strangers­
…我得能解释我究竟干了些什么
­and I'm trying to explain what I do.
所有人都知道你的价值有多大，大家都知道
Everybody knows how valuable you are. Everybody who needs to know.
我都45了，现在还穷得一个子儿也没有
I'm 45 years old and I'm broke.
我冲锋陷阵了12年，什么也没得着
I've been riding shotgun for 12 years and I got no equity.
很抱歉，我觉得心里没底
I'm sorry, I don't feel reassured.
没人让你去开酒吧啊
Nobody told you to go into the bar business.
我开酒吧是为了给自己留条后路啊，留着养老啊
I only opened it so I'd have something else, a way out.
我不知道原来你这么不开心
I had no idea you were so unhappy.
我跟你说过多少次了，把我调回诉讼团队里
How many times did I ask you to put me back on a litigation team?
-多少次啊？ -人人都能出庭辩护
-How many? -Anybody can go to court.
你觉得那样很特别么？
You think that's special?
-我擅长那个 -很好，很多人也擅长那个
-I was good at it -Wonderful. So are a lot of people.
这件事上，你所做的，很不错
At this, what you do, you're great.
看在上帝的份上，你有些东西是别人没有的，你有一个合适的职位
For chrissakes, you got something everybody wants. You have a niche.
你占有一席之地，你为自己挣得了一个合适的位置
You made a place. You made a niche for yourself.
如果你还恋旧的话…“你该看看我在皇后区当检察官时干的”
And if it's nostalgia­"You should've seen me when I was a DA back in Queens."
我给你个忠告：忘掉它吧
-Let me give you a serious piece of advice: Leave it there.
上帝不允许你像记忆中的那么好了，我看也是
God forbid you're not as good as you remember. I've seen that happen too.
但我不是来这听忠告的，不是么？
But I didn't come here for advice, did I?
那这算怎么回事？我借给你钱，要不你就不帮我搞定亚瑟？
So this is what? I give you the loan or you don't help out with Arthur?
-我可没说 -没说？
-I never said that -No?
也许你该那么说
Maybe you should have.
我不知道你打算怎么处理这事，但这件事就像癌症一样
I don't know how you're gonna take care of this, but this, this is cancer.
如果我们不迅速地控制住局面，赶快清理干净的话…
This is something, we don't get it reined in and cleaned up soon­
…那么一切都完了，一切
­everything's vulnerable. Everything.
-你想跟我说什么？ -我全靠你了
-What are you telling me? -That I'm counting on you.
我告诉你，到下周的这个时候，亚瑟要在掌控之中…
I'm telling you that by this time next week, Arthur will be under control­
…然后大家就都会记得你那无穷的价值的
­and everybody who needs to will have been reminded of your infinite value.
上帝啊，马蒂
Jesus, Marty.
嘿
Hey.
你什么时候变得他妈的这么软弱了？
When did you get so fucking delicate?
我要迟到了
I'm late.
你为什么不找吉奈叔叔请警察来帮忙呢？
Why don't you just call Uncle Gene and get the cops to help you?
不是那么回事
It's not that kind of a problem.
-我们干这个要多长时间？ -我不知道
-How much longer are we doing this? -I don't know.
如果他回来取车，你就拨这个电话告诉我
If he comes back to get his car, you call that number and let me know.
-多谢了，非常感谢 -好的，不客气
-Thank you very much. I appreciate it -Okay. You're welcome.
如果我们不是去看电影，你为什么不直说呢？
If we're not gonna get to the movie, why don't you just say so?
-什么？ -我要回家
-What? -I wanna go home.
别闹，亨利
Come on, Henry.
等下！
Hold up!
呆在车里，把门锁好
Stay in the car. Lock the door.
亚瑟！亚瑟！
Arthur! Arthur!
等等
Wait up.
迈克尔，天啊，你吓了我一跳
Michael. Jeez. You scared me.
-送货去？ -不，不，不是
-Making a delivery? -No, no, no.
挺搞笑，不是，不是那么回事
Very funny. No, nothing like that.
给，拿一根，拿着，还… 还热呢
Here, take one, please. Really. It's­  It's still warm.
这是我吃过的最香的面包
It's the best bread I ever tasted.
欢迎回来
So welcome home.
我知道，宾馆的事，很抱歉
I know, the hotel. I'm sorry.
我感觉有点儿压抑
I was beginning to feel a little overwhelmed.
-你现在感觉好些了么？ -是啊
-But you're feeling better now? -Yeah.
-好多了，确实 -还没好到能给我回电话
-Much better, definitely -Not enough to call me back.
嗯，那个，在打电话之前，我想…
Well, I was trying to gather my thoughts­
整理好我的思路，就是这么回事
­before I called you, and that's what I was doing.
那件事怎么样？
And how's that going?
很好，非常好，就是…
Yes, it's good, very good. I just­
嗯，就是我需要把思路理得更清晰些，那就是…
Well, I just need to make my thoughts a little bit more precise. That's­
那就是我的目标
That's my goal.
和这感觉一样的是你知道它会怎么发展
As good as this feels, you know where it goes.
不，不，你错了
No. No. You're wrong.
这感觉之所以好，是因为我不知道它会怎么发展
What makes this feel good is that I don't know where it goes.
我怎么跟你说呢，亚瑟？你听我的吗？
How do I talk to you, Arthur? So you hear me?
像个孩子？像个混球？还是好像一切都好？
Like a child? Like a nut? Like everything's fine?
你有什么秘密？因为我需要你听我说
What's the secret? Because I need you to hear me.
-嗯，我什么都听的 -那么听着这个
-Well, I hear everything -Then hear this.
你需要帮助，在事情无法挽回之前，你需要帮助
You need help. Before this goes too far, you need help.
你的牌很好
You got great cards here.
要是你能把衣服穿好，你爱他妈干什么就干什么
If you keep your clothes on, you can do any goddamn thing you want.
你想不干了，你就可以不干了，你想烤面包，烤去呗
You want out, you're out. You wanna bake bread, go with God.
这一大堆破事里你就办错了一件…
There's only one wrong answer in this whole goddamn pile­
…但你还护着短儿不承认
­and you've got your arms around it.
-好吧，我说了我很抱歉 -你觉得那旅馆很压抑？
-Well, I said I was sorry -You thought the hotel was overwhelming?
你让这案子难过，他们就会打断你的腿
You piss on this case, they'll cut you off at the knees.
-我不知道你在说什么 -我在给你收拾烂摊子
-I don't know what you're talking about -I'm covering for you.
我跟他们说一切都好，你很好，一切都会好的，大家都很好
I'm telling them everything's fine. You're fine. Everybody's cool.
我到处给人讲“天才的价值”的故事
I'm out running this "price of genius" story to anybody who'll listen.
但今天早上我一起来，就听说你和这个威斯康星来的姑娘联系上了
And then I wake up this morning and I hear you're calling this girl from Wisconsin­
…还有什么该死的文件和其他一些破烂儿
­messing with documents and whatever else.
-你怎么知道的？ -他们掌控着一切
-How can you know that? -They're gonna take everything.
你的合伙身份、你的流通股，他们会吊销你的执照
Your partnership, your equity. They're gonna pull your license.
-你怎么知道我给安娜打了电话？ -马蒂告诉我的
-How do you know I called Anna? -Marty told me.
-那么，他怎么知道的？ -我不知道，我可没胡扯！
-Well, how does he know? -I don't know. I don't give a shit!
-你在窃听我的电话 -天啊，亚瑟
-You're tapping my phone -Jesus, Arthur.
那么解释一下，告诉我马蒂怎么知道的！
Then explain it. Tell me how Marty knows!
因为你晃着小弟弟追着个姑娘跑过了整个停车场
Because you're chasing a girl through a parking lot with your dick hanging out.
你觉得她不会拿起电话打给她的律师么？
You think she didn't get off the phone and dial her attorney?
不，她不会那么做的，我清楚这一点
No. She wouldn't do that. I know that.
真的？你认为你的判断力已经达到“艺术欣赏”的水平了么？
Really? You think your judgment is state-of-the-art right now?
他们准备要亮底牌了，你得停下来好好想想
They're putting everything on the table. You need to stop and think this through.
我会帮你一起想的
I'll help you think this through.
我会找人帮你想想的
I'll find somebody to help you think it through.
别这样，你这样会便宜了他们
Don't do this. You're making it easy for them.
迈克尔，我非常喜欢你的为人
Michael, I have great affection for you.
你过着丰富多彩的生活，但你只是个跑腿的，不是辩护律师
You lead a very rich and interesting life, but you're a bagman, not an attorney.
如果你想要控告我…
If you wanted to have me committed­
你最好让我呆在威斯康星州，那里有逮捕记录
­you should have kept me in Wisconsin, where the arrest report, the videotape­
…录像带和目击证人来证明我有不当行为…
­and eyewitness accounts of my inappropriate behavior­
…那里才有审判管辖权
­would have had jurisdictional relevance.
我在纽约州没有任何犯罪记录
I have no criminal record in the state of New York.
对于非自愿监禁的唯一判断标准就是威胁性
And the single determining criterion for involuntary incarceration is danger.
被告是否对自己或者他人造成了威胁？
Is the defendant a danger to himself or others?
你觉得你整明白了吗？
You think you got the horses for that?
好了，祝你好运，愿上帝保佑你，但我要告诉你：
Well, good luck and God bless. But I tell you this:
你绝对不会愿意在法庭上见到我的
The last place you want to see me is in court.
我不是你的敌人
I'm not the enemy.
那你是谁？
Then who are you?
我们发现种子
We find the seed.
我们保育土壤
We shape the soil.
我们加速收获
We speed the harvest.
我们抚育星球
We feed the planet.
我们发现种子
We find the seed.
我们保育土壤
We shape the soil.
我们加速收获
We speed the harvest.
我们抚育星球
We feed the planet.
这小子干啥呢？
What the hell is he doing?
我们发现种子
We find the seed.
您现在访问的是肯纳、巴赫和莱迪恩事务所亚瑟·伊顿的语音信箱
You've reached the voicemail of Arthur Edens at Kenner, Bach & Ledeen.
请在提示音后留言
Please leave your message after the tone.
好啊！
Yes!
是我啊，大伙，大家都在听吗？
Here we are, all together. Is everyone listening?
这就是你们期待已久的时刻，一页非常特别的报告
This is the moment you've been waiting for. A very special piece of paper.
让我们用充满病态和恶意的掌声欢迎…
So let's have a big, paranoid, malignant round of applause­
北地联合克林泰特内部研究备忘录229号
­  for United Northfield Culcitate Internal Research Memorandum 229.
1991年1月19日发布
June 19th, 1991.
结论如下：
"Conclusion:
克林泰特所取得的出乎意料的市场增长…
The unanticipated market growth for Culcitate­
是基于小型农庄在寒冷气候下的即时成本—利益分析
­by small farms in colder climates demands immediate cost-benefit analysis."
你们这帮家伙想不想听点儿法律建议？
Would you guys like a little bit of legal advice?
永远不要让科学家把“出乎意料”…
Never let a scientist use the words "unanticipated"­
…和“即时”放在一个句子里
­and "immediate" in the same sentence.
明白了吧？好的
Okay? Okay.
内部土地试验显示…
"In-house field studies have indicated­
小型短期农庄人类活动所必需的井水…
­  that small short-season farms dependent on well water for human consumption­
其中的毒素颗粒有聚集到…
­  are at risk for toxic particulate concentrations at levels­
…能够对人体组织造成损害的程度的风险
­significant enough to cause serious human tissue damage."
这个么，绕了半天，就是要说…
Well, this is a long way of saying that­
你都不用离开房子就能被我们的产品干掉了
­you don't even have to leave your house to be killed by our product.
我们把毒药直接送到你们家厨房
We'll pipe it into your kitchen sink.
-克林泰特它无味、无色而且不易凝结… -把电话给我
-"Culcitate's great market advantage­ -Give me the phone.
这所谓的巨大市场优势…
­  that it is tasteless, colorless and does not precipitate­
有可能掩盖并加强…
­  has the potential to mask and intensify­
…露天放置导致的潜在致命威胁
­these potentially lethal exposures."
现在，我喜欢这东西了
Now, I love this.
这不仅是个伟大的产品…
Not only is this a great product­
…还是个超级癌症制造系统
­it is a superb cancer delivery system.
克林泰特产品化学成份的改变…
"Chemical modifications of the Culcitate product­
添加某种检测分子，比如气味分子或有色分子…
­  the addition of a detector molecule, such as an odorant or colorant­
…将会需要自上而下地重新设计克林泰特的整个生产工序
­  would require a top-down redesign of the Culcitate manufacturing process.
这方面的花费，由于太过巨大…
These costs, while assumed to be significant­
…将不在此处进行计算
­  were not summarized here. "
这个么，笼统地说，意思就是：
Which, loosely translated, means:
这玩意儿改好要破好大一笔财，而我就是个实验室里的小喽啰…
"It's going to cost a fortune to go back on this, and I'm just an asshole in a lab­
…因此有没有别人能做个决定啊？
­so could someone else please make the decision?"
很明显，这份内部研究文档的发布…
"Clearly, the release of these internal research documents­
将会动摇克林泰特的有效市场份额…
­  would compromise the effective marketing of Culcitate­
因此必须被定为…
­and must be kept within the protective confines­
北地联合公司的商业机密
­of United-Northfield's trade secret language."
你们不需要我给你们解释了吧
You don't need me to tell you what that means.
再见
Goodbye.
-看来我要… -是
-It seemed to warrant my coming to­ -Yes.
你必须要控制住局势
You have to contain this.
-控制住？ -对
-Contain? -Right.
好吧，那是我的问题
Well, that's my question.
我们…？我们有什么解决方案么？
What are the­? What's the option that we're looking at?
对于这个情况
Along those lines.
你是说那些文件、数据？我不知…
You're talking about the paper, the data? I don't­
嗯，我在想是不是还有其他选择
Well, I'm wondering if there is some other option.
我是说有什么我没想到的？
I mean something I'm not thinking of?
我们什么都能干
We deal in absolutes.
好的，我明白，我明白了
Okay. I understand that. I do.
那些材料、资料，我又不是律师，我们试试看，尽力吧
The material, the papers, I'm not a lawyer. We try, we do what we can.
嗯，其他手段呢？
Well, the other way?
其他手段
Is the other way.
-也许你该把丹找来处理这事 -不
-Maybe you wanna bring Don in on this -No.
这事和丹没关系，他很忙，这和他没关系
This is nothing to do with Don. He's busy. This is nothing to do with Don.
你觉得可行么？
Do you think it's doable?
嗯，我们有些好主意，你说行动，我们就行动
Yeah. We have some good ideas. You say move, we move.
如果这主意看起来不怎么好，我们就按兵不动，再想想看
If the ideas don't look so good, we back off, reassess­
好吧
Okay.
你的意思是“好吧，你明白了”还是“好吧，行动”？
Is that, "Okay, you understand," or "Okay, proceed"?
你1岁？你2岁？你3岁？
Are you 1? Are you 2? Are you 3?
你4岁？你5岁？你6岁？
Are you 4? Are you 5? Are you 6?
-你7岁？你8岁？你9岁？ -行了
-Are you 7? Are you 8? Are you 9? -Come on.
行了，行了，我说了，嘿！
Come, come on. Come on, I said. Hey!
别说了
Come on.
好了，爸爸，许愿吧
Go on, Dad, make a wish.
要是愿望成真，我就爽死了
If I get what I wish for, it'll kill me.
你是个狂人，不可思议
You're a maniac. Unbelievable.
帮我一把，埃迪，哈？
Give me a hand, Eddie, huh?
好的，埃迪
All right, Eddie.
嗯，不是我自己做的，不好吃别赖我
Now, I did not make this myself and I don't wanna hear any complaints.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
你有时间吃蛋糕么？
You have time for cake?
有，有啊，我吃一块再走
Yeah, yeah. I'll take one to go.
要走了？
You going in?
-我已经迟到了 -该死
-I'm late already -Shit.
你俩不是都没钱了吧？
You're not both running out?
我有点儿状况
I got a situation.
-你挺不住了 -你要走了
-You can't hang? -You're going in.
-是啊，我要轮班 -我也有
-Yeah. I got a shift -So do I.
得了吧，伙计，好几个月你都没来了
Come on, man. You haven't been up here in months.
要是你现在就回去，米奇(迈克尔的昵称)，亨利要留在这儿
If you go back now, Mickey, Henry's staying here.
好吧，你可以开车送他回去
Good. You can drive him home.
就呆一个小时
Just stay for an hour.
姑娘们才干这事呢
The girls did all this stuff.
他那时候就睡着了
He'll be asleep by then.
提米给我打电话了
Timmy's been calling me.
他不敢跟你谈
He's afraid to talk to you.
他是不敢
He should be.
-清仓不怎么顺利，是吧？ -他是这么跟你说的？
-It closed out bad, right? -Is that what he told you?
孩子们都吓坏了
The kids are freaking out.
亲戚们也吓坏了
The in-laws are freaking out.
帕米害怕得哭个不停
Pammy can't stop crying long enough to start freaking out.
-她把他领回去了 -那能怎样？去他妈的老婆孩子？
-She took him back -So what? Fuck her and the kids?
不，去他妈的提米，一切都没完，明白么？
No. Fuck Timmy. And nothing's closed, okay?
我把所有东西都卖了，但我们还是差点儿，所以别老提什么帕米和孩子
I sold everything and we're still short. So don't talk about Pammy and the kids.
我全担下来了
I got my hands full.
这事要是你，他就不会这么懒
If it was you, he'd be in traction.
好了，他病了，行了吧？
Yeah, he's sick, all right?
-他有病，那是种病 -这观点挺新鲜
-He's sick. It's a sickness -There's a fresh perspective.
最近我看到不少人旧瘾复发，到处都是
I've seen a lot of people falling off the wagon lately. It's going around.
你是在说我么？
Is that pointed at me?
我什么时候见过你？我怎么知道你都在忙啥？
When do I see you? How do I know what you're up to?
我有一年多没赌钱了
I haven't bet on a game in over a year.
我有10个月没进过扑克室了
I haven't been in a card room in 10 months.
我把宝押在了酒吧上，押在了提米身上，结果他给我搞砸了
I gambled on the bar. I bet on Timmy and he wiped me out.
那就是我的大买卖，行了吧？
That was my big play, all right?
我把养老的钱都投进去了，现在没了，我穷困潦倒
I put up my walk-away money and it's gone and I'm scrambling.
好了，好了
Okay. Okay.
冷静点儿，我听着呢
Cool down. I hear you.
我也被耍了
I'd be pissed off too.
等1个小时就好
Just hang for an hour.
-好么？ -好吧
-Okay? -Yeah.
准备好了？好，抬
Ready? And, lift.
预备，走
Ready and go.
擦擦
Wipe.
你可以扎了
You better hit it.
搞定了
We're good.
好的，我找到了，这是他的号码
Okay, I found it. That's his number.
穆林大夫，看你的运气了
Dr.Mullien. See if you have any more luck.
好吧，如果我能，我一有机会就去
If I can. As soon as I get a chance.
有医疗补助的，我们都有，我可以给你文件…
It's Medicaid. They're running us in circles. I can pull the file­
让他走吧，斯蒂芬，他有约会
Let him go, Steph. He's got a date.
我和一个疯狂律师有约
I've got a date with a maniac attorney.
-晚上别工作了，米奇 -你看起来很疲倦
-Take a night off, Mickey -You look tired.
-我没事，回见 -好好的
-I'm okay. See you soon -Be good.
-好了，再见 -再见，亨利
-All right. Bye -Bye, Hen.
-再见，爸爸 -再见
-Bye, Pop -Bye.
-提米叔叔，你好啊！ -你怎么样啊，亨利？
-Uncle Timmy, hey! -How you doing, Henry?
亨利，快上车
Henry, get in the car.
见到你很高兴，亨利
Good to see you, Hen.
-你想要什么？ -我已经戒酒8天了
-What do you want? -I've been sober eight days now.
出来见几个面，我想让你知道
Been back at the meetings. I wanted you to know.
在孩子面前？
In front of the kid?
米奇，求你了，我知道我曾经有多坏，我发誓
Mickey, please. I know how bad I did, I swear.
我不知道该怎么走上正轨，我满脑子想的都是这个
I don't know how to make it right again. It's all I think about.
我该怎么做？我知道干什么
What do I do? I don't know what to do.
把轮胎还给斯蒂芬娜
Get Stephanie her tires back.
-他哭了？ -不知道
-Is he crying? -I don't know.
因为吸了毒，是么？
Because of drugs, right?
差不多就那玩意儿
That and everything else.
怎么了？
What?
你提米叔叔…
Your Uncle Timmy­
我是说，在他最风光的时候也没有像你这样坚强
­and I mean this, on his best day, is never as tough as you.
我不是说他哭了，或者吸毒什么的
I'm not talking about crying or the drugs or anything.
我是在说他的心，内心里，你明白么？
I'm talking about in his heart, in his heart. You understand me?
他就会胡诌，吹的天花乱坠的
And all his charming bullshit, this Big Tim, Uncle, Boss bullshit­
…我知道你爱他，我知道为什么
­and I know you love him, and I know why.
但当你看见他那熊样…
But when you see him like that­
…你不必担心，你不会成为那样的人的
­you don't have to worry. That's not how it'll be for you.
你不会成为那种天天慨叹…
You're not gonna be someone that goes through life­
…为什么自己老是踩到臭狗屎的人
­wondering why shit keeps falling out of the sky around them.
我知道，我知道这一点
I know that. I know it.
明白么？
Okay?
每次我看着你我都能看出这一点来，我现在就能看到
I see it every time I look at you. I see it right now.
我不知道你是从哪儿获得的，但你确实有
I don't know where you got it from, but you got it.
明白么？
Okay?
喂
Hello?
邻居过来了，他们在修理楼下的阁楼
The neighbors came by. They're renovating the loft downstairs.
他们发现有水流从他的盥洗室流到下面
They had water flooding from his bathroom down to their place.
他的前门、紧急通道，都被他锁得严严实实
His front door, fire escape, he had everything locked up pretty good.
我的人花了10分钟才进去，还不得不把门砸掉
It took our guys 10 minutes. They had to knock the thing down.
到处都是药丸
There's pills all over the place.
完全就是自杀的现场
Just the scene alone is pretty definitive for suicide.
然后我问了一些最近处理过这种事的…
Then I spoke to some of your partners­
你的老熟人，因此…
­who ran down these problems he'd been having lately, so­
-有遗言么？ -没有，他们看过了
-Is there a note? -No. They looked.
可能是个意外或者他本打算写遗言但没写成
It could be an accident or he was gonna write a note and just messed up.
我能进去么？
Can I get in there?
他的住处？现在不行，已经封闭了
His place? Not now. It's sealed.
一旦现场封闭，一切都冻结了，我们会试着联系他的女儿
Once the seal goes up, it's frozen. We're gonna try and reach his daughter.
我想她在欧洲，但她就要回来了
I guess she's off in Europe. But she's gotta come in.
还要等尸检官的毒物报告检测结果
Or the M.E.'s gotta come back with a toxicology report.
至少要花几周的时间，只能那样了
That's a couple of weeks at least that it's gotta stay like that.
抱歉
Sorry.
没事
Sure.
好吧
Okay.
我认识你弟弟，我妻子在皇后区那边做事
I know your brother a little. My wife works the 190 out in Queens.
代我向他问好
I'll tell him hello.
如果有什么新情况，我会和你联系的
If something comes in, I'll get back to you.
好的，谢谢你
Yeah. I appreciate it.
对您的损失感到很难过
I'm sorry for your loss.
-迈克尔 -杰夫
-Michael -Jeff.
这真难过
This is tough.
是，是啊，他在这儿么？
Yeah, it is. He in here?
沉默寡言的混球
Dumb son of a bitch.
多么可怕
What a thing.
-稍等 -我都不知道…
-Hold on -I don't even know­
-真抱歉 -嗯，没关系
-I'm so sorry -Yeah. All right.
我都没机会和他聊聊
I didn't even get a chance to talk to him.
那个该死的老疯子
That crazy goddamn bastard.
多大的损失啊，他到底在想什么？
What a waste. What the hell was he thinking?
马蒂？我得处理一下这事
Marty? I gotta set this up.
去，去吧
Go. Go.
你还好吧？
You okay?
嗯，还好
Yeah, I'm fine.
来，咱们喝一杯
Come on, let's get you a drink.
我一直在回味这件事，比如，是不是我给他的压力太大了？
I just keep replaying all this back. Like, did I push him too hard?
不可能
Not a chance.
我一直没法和他沟通
I just couldn't get through to him.
得了，你把他吓死了？算了吧，那家伙倔得像头牛
What, you scared him to death? Come on. The man was a bull.
-不是那样的 -他后来为什么屈服了？为什么他…？
-Never happened -Why does he fold, then? Why does he­?
那一定是场意外
It's gotta be an accident.
不，不可能，亚瑟会没留下便条？
No, no. Arthur without a note?
他连撒个尿都要写个备忘录呢，一定是意外
He couldn't piss without leaving a memo. Has to be an accident.
我不相信，我搞不明白
I don't get that. I don't understand that either.
前一分钟他还打算控制全世界…
One minute he's gonna take on the whole world­
…12小时之后，他却自行了断了，为什么呢？
­and then 12 hours later, he's sucking down pills. Why?
为什么？
Why?
因为所有人都是他妈的不可理喻的，“为什么？”
Because people are fucking incomprehensible. "Why?"
我认识亚瑟30年了
Thirty years I know Arthur.
好日子啊
Good years.
如果我够诚实，我现在的感觉是什么？
And what I feel right now, if I'm honest?
我说不出来，太糟了
I can't even say, it's so awful.
你能说的
You can say it.
我们只不过比他幸运些
We caught a lucky break.
确实啊，不是么？
We did, didn't we?
马蒂？我们得去一下办公室
Marty? We need to get up to the office.
-他们同意了？ -原则上
-They accepted? -In principle.
丹·杰弗瑞要我们半小时内听电话
Don Jeffries wants us on the phone in half an hour.
我试着解释亚瑟的事，但他们没有什么同情心
I tried to explain about Arthur, but they're short on sympathy.
等一下，U/North自己处理的？
Wait a minute. U/North is settling?
他们看到了一线希望，他们想试试，这是他们的事，我们能干什么？
They see a window. They wanna try. It's their show. What are we gonna do?
你尽力了，迈克尔，我们都尽力了
You did what you could, Michael. We all did.
这是…
It's­
这就是我们得到的
It's what we got.
-你需要送一下么？ -不，谢了，我很好
-You need a ride? -No, thanks, I'm fine.
喂
Hello.
喂，你好，我找安娜·凯泽森
Hello. Hi. I'm looking for Anna Kysersun.
你是谁？
Who is this?
迈克尔·克莱顿，我是纽约的一名律师，我是从亚瑟那里得到你的号码的
Michael Clayton. I'm an attorney in New York. I got your number from Arthur.
-你们可真有种阿 -什么？
-You have got some nerve -Excuse me?
你们让她飞到纽约去，还把她一个人留在机场？
You get her all the way to New York City and then leave her at the airport?
她是个单纯的人
This is not a complicated person.
这姑娘从来没去过比密尔沃基远的地方
This is a girl who's never been farther than Milwaukee.
-等一下，等等 -不，你等着
-Wait a minute. Now, wait -No, you wait.
她明天就要回家了，她回来以后，你们要是再…
She's coming home tomorrow and when she does, if you call here again­
你是说她现在在纽约么？
Are you telling me she's in New York right now?
这还是个小姑娘，你听着没有？
This is a young girl, do you hear me?
她现在就在城里？
She's in the city right now?
你是什么人？
What kind of people are you?
听着，等我一会儿，就一会儿
Listen. You just stay on the phone one second. One second.
安娜
Anna.
安娜？
Anna?
我叫迈克尔·克莱顿，是亚瑟的一个朋友
My name's Michael Clayton. I'm a friend of Arthur's.
我问了你姐姐，她说你在这儿
I spoke with your sister. She told me you were here.
请开开门，安娜
Please open the door, Anna.
你怎么看？
What are you thinking?
不知道，我望风，你去搜他的车，找点儿线索
I don't know. I'll watch the door. You check his car. Let's get some details.
他没有详细说是怎么回事
He didn't want to say exactly what it was.
就说我来了之后，他会来接我…
Just that when I got here, he would pick me up­
然后给我看些东西，我会见到…
­and show me, and I would see­
…能使整件案子翻盘的东西
­that it was something that would win the whole case.
即使在今天早上…
Even this morning­
…我是说，我想：
­I mean, I thought:
好吧，如果我到了机场没有票的话我就明白了
"Okay, if I get to the airport and the ticket's not there, then I'll know.
好了，你很蠢，你可以回家了
Okay, you're stupid, and you can go home now."
但确实有票，他付过钱了，好像是800块…
But it was there and he paid, like, 800 dollars­
…一张头等舱
­for a first-class ticket.
我只是…
And I just­
我上了飞机
I got on the plane.
我相信他了
I believed him.
你有没有觉得他可能在某种程度上来说感到失望了？
You think maybe he was in some way disappointed?
这么说吧，他知道你告诉了其他人这一切…
Let's say that he knew that you told somebody else about all of this­
…然后，我也说不大好，在某些程度上，他对你那样做感到失望？
­and, I don't know, in some crazy way, he was disappointed by that?
-但我没那么做 -你一定是跟别人说了
-But I didn't -You must have told somebody else.
没有
No.
他让我发誓了
He made me promise.
你没跟别人讲这件事？一个都没有？
You didn't tell anybody else about this? Not one other person?
没有
No.
他其实是真疯了，不是么？
He really was crazy, wasn't he?
-你是说这个么？ -让我看看
-You talking about this? -Let me see.
-你知道这是什么吗？ -知道
-You know what that is? -Yeah.
你就说帮个“小忙”，这可比“小忙”大多了
You said a favor. That's more than a favor.
好了，没人知道这是从哪儿来的
Well, nobody's gonna know where it came from.
-是你那事耽搁了么？ -你什么意思？
-Are you that jammed up? -What are you talking about?
谁需要这玩意儿？是餐馆的事，是吧？
Who asked for this? It's the restaurant, right?
是你的某个债主么？“给我搞个封条”
One of these guys you owe? "Get me a seal."
你真的想知道么？
You really wanna know?
这事越来越有意思了
This just gets better and better.
我们干点儿什么呢？
What are we doing?
(“最佳打印”委托印刷清单)
别动！
Freeze!
呆着别动，你个混蛋！别动！
Right there, asshole! Don't move!
-好吧，我没恶意，我是个朋友！ -举起手来！
-It's all right, I'm a friend! -Get your hands up!
快把手举起来！快点儿！
Get your hands up now! Now!
-你手里是什么？ -是本书
-What's in your hand? -It's a book.
放下！快放下！快点儿！
Drop it! Drop it, now! Drop it!
-转过来，慢点儿 -好的，好的，转了
-Turn around. Slowly -All right. All right. Okay.
-这儿还有谁？ -没别人了
-Who else is here? -Nobody.
-我在问你，这儿还有谁？ -没有别人了！
-I said, who else is here? -Nobody's here!
查一下那边
Check in there.
你要是敢动，就打爆你的头
You move, I'll take your head off.
现在我欠这家伙和我部门里他那混蛋老婆的情
Now I owe this scumbag and his wife­ Who's a complete piece of shit in my unit.
-现在我把命都押上了 -很抱歉
-Now I owe them both my balls -I'm sorry.
-你了解我的 -不是说“没人会知道的”么
-You know I am -"Nobody will know it's me."
他们要是发现了怎么办，发现是我给的你那该死的…
You know what happens they don't bury this, that I gave you this?
很糟糕，我知道了
It's bad. I know it.
我还有18个月就工作满20你年了，你的举动让我的退休金岌岌可危
I'm 18 months away from my 20. You just put my pension in jeopardy.
-你终于说到“重点”了 -那不是什么重点！
-You made your point -It's not a point!
-谁报的警？ -什么？
-Who called 911? -What?
大楼空无一人，我是轻手轻脚的，我都没呆多长时间
The building was empty. I was quiet. I wasn't there very long.
谁叫警察来的？这些你有没有想过这事…？
Who called it in? Does that make sense to you­?
这事结了
This never happened.
你让警察觉得你是个律师
You got these cops thinking you're a lawyer.
你让律师觉得你是个警察
You got these lawyers thinking you're a cop.
你把大伙都骗了，不是么？除你之外所有人
You got everybody fooled, don't you? Everybody but you.
你很清楚自己是个什么东西
You know exactly what you are.
我们给你打过6次电话
We tried calling you six times.
但你的答录机一定是坏了还是怎么的
But your machine must be busted or something.
这是我们最好的技术
We gave it our best shot.
我们的红色封面用完了，库存只有2000…
We ran out of red covers. We only had 2000 in stock­
…因此剩下的1000我们用了蓝色的
­so we did the other thousand in blue.
(内部使用) (北地联合克林泰特除草剂内部研究备忘录229号)
没什么问题吧？
Is everything all right?
啊，没问题
It's fine, yeah.
嗯，你开车了么？因为后面还有25箱…
You have a van or something? Because I have 25 boxes back there­
帮我个忙，看好它们
Do me a favor. Hang on to them.
我下周回来把这些都拉走
I'll come back and pick everything up next week.
-真的么？谢了，伙计 -好的
-Seriously? Thanks, man -Yeah.
喂
Hello.
丹，你们先走，我随后就到
Don. You go ahead. I'll catch up to you.
什么？
What?
你认识迈克尔·克莱顿么？
Do you know Michael Clayton?
认识，怎么了？
Yeah, why?
我们遇到了新情况
We have a situation.
嘿，他们找到你了吗？
Hey, did they find you?
-谁找我？ -马蒂，我想他们还在
-Who? -Marty. I don't think they've gone in yet.
马蒂
Marty.
你电话关机了，好多事都找不着你
Your phone's off. There's too much going on for your phone to be off.
-我要单独聊聊 -你看，那个，我们要晚了…
-I need a minute -Yeah, well, we're late­
我们昨天晚上还没做完呢
We never got to finish last night.
你是最后走的吗？看起来气色很差
Did you close the place? You look like hell.
-不是，你走之后我就走了 -如果是那样的话
-No, I left right after you left -If you say so.
我们忙了一晚上，我们必须发表一项声明
We've been here all night. We had to make an announcement.
简！我需要那个，给我个信封
Jean! I need the thing, the envelope.
我本想让你加入进来，但找不到你，我只好做了决定
I wanted your input. I couldn't get you. I had to pull the trigger.
我让鲍勃·奈斯特和金，可能是用错了
I put Bob Nast and Kim, probably a mistake.
他们打算这周末举办一个追悼仪式
They're gonna pull together a memorial service by the end of the week.
我跟他们说了需要帮忙就找你
I told them to call you if they need any help.
不、不，不是，另一个，另一个
No, no, no. The other one. The other one.
我们今早给你开了张支票
So we cut you a check this morning.
但有些附加条件，巴里…
There's some strings attached. And Barry­
这事没商量，巴里必须参与进来
There's no way around this, Barry's gonna have to be involved.
如果亚瑟是在追查某件事情呢？
What if Arthur was on to something?
你什么意思？追查什么？
What do you mean? On to what?
U/North，如果他没疯？如果他是对的呢？
U/North. What if he wasn't crazy? What if he was right?
什么对了？我们站错了队？
Right about what? That we're on the wrong side?
站错了队，走错了路，一切，一切都不对
Wrong side, wrong way, everything, all of it.
这事新鲜么？这案子从第一天起就臭不可闻
This is news? This case reeked from day one.
你都呆了15年了，还要我告诉你我们是怎么赚钱的吗？
I gotta tell you how we pay the rent?
他们会怎么做？如果他把事实公之于众呢？
What would they do? What would they do if he went public?
他们会怎么做？你他妈的傻了吧？他们已经这么做了
What would they do? Are you fucking soft? They're doing it.
如果我们不能在24小时内彻底解决这事…
We don't straighten the settlement out in 24 hours­
…他们就会拒绝支付900万的律师费
­they're gonna withhold $9 million in fees.
然后他们还会公布亚瑟在密尔沃基跳脱衣舞的录像
Then they'll pull out the video of Arthur doing his flashdance.
他们会起诉我们玩忽职守
They'll sue us for legal malpractice.
除了这些之外，与伦敦的合并案也会告吹…
Except there won't be anything to win because the London merger will be dead­
…大伙就只能回家喝西北风去了
­and we'll be selling off the goddamn furniture.
这是8万块
That's 80.
我们管它就叫奖金
We're calling it a bonus.
你以现在的年薪续约3年
Three-year contract at your current numbers.
那奖金是将给那个的
That's assuming this all works out.
你现在就办了？
You're doing this now?
我说，我同意这么办，好吧？但有条件的
Look, I agreed to this, okay? But there's rules now.
你想要合同，就得签订一份保密协议
You want the contract, you sign a confidentiality agreement.
协议内容不能更改，同时具有追溯效力
It's gonna be bulletproof and retroactive.
因为马蒂这人很友善，不愿意说…
Because Marty's too nice to say it­
…但就你对这地方的了解，客户和在这儿工作的员工…
­but with all you know about this place, the clients and people who work here­
…都会对你要价8万块感到有点儿奇怪
­it makes it a little weird when you ask for 80 grand.
我要是勒索别人，第一个先找你…
If I was gonna shake anybody down, I'd come to you­
…而且肯定不会只要8万块，这是你的意思还是他的？
­and it wouldn't be for 80 grand. Is this him or you?
-如果我错了，我道歉 -你他妈的完全错了
-If I'm wrong, I apologize -You're way the fuck wrong.
随你便好了
So there you go.
够了，你俩，行了吧？
Enough. Okay? Everybody.
他是个混蛋，但他清楚地知道这一点
He's an asshole, but he knows it.
你呢，是公认的(混蛋)，好了吧？大家都高兴了？
And you're on the record. Okay? Everybody happy?
-丹·杰弗瑞来了 -我们就到
-Don Jeffries is here -We're on the way.
和鲍勃·奈斯特联系一下，看看他们需要帮忙不
Call Bob Nast. Just see if they need help with this thing.
欢迎回来
You're welcome.
你说是1万2，这可是7万5啊
You said 12. This is 75.
嗯，别激动，你要来一杯吗？
Well, don't get too excited. You want a drink?
不，我上班呢
No. I'm working.
现在我们扯平了，那么，不用干别的了
So we're square, then. No bad blood.
你只是在尽自己的职责罢了
You're just doing your job.
是啊
That's right.
保重，盖比
Take it easy, Gabe.
你也一样
Michael.
不跟
Check.
-不跟 -半注，两百
-Check -Half the pot. Two hundred.
两百胜
Two hundred to go.
那么，餐馆现在怎么样了
So, what happened with the bar?
看来你经营的不善啊，哈？
You just had to be a rock star, huh?
你干什么？你才刚来
What are you doing? You just got here.
这哥们儿才玩了9手，这就走了
Guy plays nine hands, walks away.
我把你吓跑了？我干了什么？是我把你吓跑了吗？
I scare you away? What did I do? Did I scare you away?
快走
Get out.
快离开车子
Get out of the car now.
-沃尔特？ -迈克尔
-Walter? -Michael.
-迈克尔，谢天谢地，总算找到你 -嗯
-Michael. Thank God you're there -Yeah.
你还有8秒…
You have eight­
6、5…
­  six, five­
4、3…
­  four, three­
快走
Get out of the car.
-告诉他不要接任何电话了 -好的，你会去吧？
-Tell him to stay off the phone -All right. But you're on it?
我没被发现吧？
Am I clean?
接着走
Just keep walking.
收到，我没被发现吧？
You copy. Am I clean?
走就是了，他正朝他的车走去
Just keep moving. He's walking to the car.
你只要在路上就行了，我会给你带来更多的细节
-to let him know you're on the way. I'll get back to you with the details.
-给我2分钟 -我马上开车去
-Just give me two minutes -I'll be in the car.
我没安完，是装上了，但不知道能不能用
I didn't finish. It's in, but I don't know.
不是很好，有点儿杂波，他就在前边，但是…
It's loose. I got a pulse. He's up there somewhere, but­
我来看看能不能增强下信号
Let's find a way to boost the signal.
-我不知道沃尔特给了你什么承诺… -一位天才员工！
-I don't know what Walter promised you­ -A miracle worker!
沃尔特在电话里是这么说的，20分钟前，原话要听么，啊？
That's Walter on the phone, 20 minutes ago. Direct quote, okay?
“挺住，我会派一个天才来帮助你”
"I'm sending you a miracle worker."
-喔，那他说错了 -哪儿说错了？
-Well, he misspoke -About what?
关于你是公司的救火员那部份？还是你根本就不在行？
About the fact that you're the firm's fixer? Or that you're any good at it?
我们走，有信号了
We're up. Just got a signal.
这条路上毫无人烟，他在干什么？
There's nothing back this way. What's he doing?
也许他迷路了
Maybe he's lost.
-等一下 -他来了
-Wait a minute -That's him.
他一个人，是吧？
He was alone, right?
-是，我觉得是 -确定点儿，是还是不是？
-Yeah, I think so -Call it, yes or no?
我们得调头回去
We gotta turn around.
说话啊
Talk to me.
讯号断断续续的
It's strobing.
不，走得对，我想我们走得对，接着开
No, we're good. I think we're good. Just keep going.
不，他转弯了，不知道为什么他转弯了
No, he turned. Somehow he turned.
-哪儿？ -他在…
-Where? -He took­
-他转左了 -左边哪儿有叉路啊
-He took a left -I don't have a left.
-东面，他在东南面 -什么，我们跟丢了？
-East. He's southeast -What, so we missed it?
-可能是地图有问题 -别着急
-Or the grid is wrong -Hang on.
-我们得回到原点 -原点是什么？哪算原点？
-We gotta go back to one -One is what? Where's our one?
直走半英里，一直开，开就是了
Half a mile straight ahead. Just keep driving. Just go.
现实是我们接近了，但那是西面，不是东边
It says we're closing. But that's west. It can't be west.
信号还是地图的问题？
The signal or the grid?
-可能都有，讯号减弱了 -该死的
-It's both. It just keeps dropping out -Goddamn it.
把电话给我
Give me the cell.
我们的信号很好
Our signaI's good.
怎么了？
What?
谢了，米奇
Thanks, Mickey.
带我离开这儿
Just get me out of here.
我要这个会议的时间安排表，越快越好，最晚周四
I wanna get a meeting scheduled on this, soon as we can. Thursday at the latest.
我觉得我们得找个来自裁决组的人，麦克戴尔可以…
I think we should have someone from the equity group there. Maybe McDonnell­
-嗯？ -你听说了么？
-Yeah? -Did you hear?
-是啊，听说了，U/North结案了 -不是，是迈克尔·克莱顿的事
-Yeah, yeah. They closed U/North -No. Michael Clayton.
什么？
What?
汽车炸弹，远郊，今天早晨，他被杀了
Car bomb. Upstate. This morning. He was killed.
什么？
What?
天啊
Holy shit.
U/North公司依然坚持认为这场诉讼是…
It has been and it remains the U/North position­
证据不足而且毫无道理可言的
­  that this lawsuit is baseless and without merit.
基于原告方要求支付超过30亿美元的赔偿金…
Our reluctance to negotiate was anchored by this belief­
我们的态度和以前一样，甚至更坚决…
­and reinforced by the plaintiffs' demand for settlement­
…不愿谈判
­in excess of 3 billion dollars.
但今天我们聚集在这里…
The reason that we are all here today is­
…是因为本案的一些关键因素已经发生了变化
­that several key elements in the case have changed.
你们手中都有一份计划中的一揽子解决方案…
You all have a tentative proposal packet­
…上面标出了细节，关键之处在于这点：
­  which outlines the details, but the bottom line is this:
在过去的几个月里，有消息指出…
Over the past several months we had gotten word­
原告的耐心开始不足…
­that the plaintiffs were growing impatient­
…他们正在修改要求赔偿金的数目
­and were in the process of revising their settlement numbers.
我们也了解到…
We also learned­
原告的律师费上限为32%…
­  that the plaintiffs' attorneys' fees were capped at 32 percent­
最高4亿美元…
­  up to 400 million dollars­
…超过的部份，律师费将降为24%
­above which, their fees dropped to 24 percent.
因此我们知道这种两难的境地让他们…
So we knew that there would be this motivational dead zone for them­
…止步不前
­in the middle there.
最后…
Finally­
…我们的财务部门告知我们他们计算出了
­our finance team informed us that they had run the numbers­
赔偿金及税款的总额…
­and that the tax benefit­
如果我们能将赔偿金控制在6亿美元以下…
­provided that we bring the settlement in under 600 million­
在这一财政年度内…
­and within this fiscal year­
…公司业绩就可以弥补赔偿金带来的损失
­that the write-off on this settlement would essentially pay for itself.
你们面前的一揽子解决方案，就我看来…
The package that you have before you represents, in my judgment­
…是公司在目前情况下的最好选择
­  the strongest possible position for our company under the circumstances.
同时，作为首席顾问…
And, as chief counsel­
…我建议你们通过这一方案
­it is my recommendation that this proposal be confirmed.
谢谢你，凯伦，我们需要几分钟时间来讨论一下这个问题
Thank you, Karen. If you just give us a few minutes to talk about it.
好的，我在外面等
Certainly. I'll be right outside.
嗯…
Well­
里面情况怎么样？
How'd it go in there?
吓坏了吧，哈？
Pretty freaky, huh?
你看见亚瑟了么？他就在附近出没
Did you see Arthur? He's wandering around here somewhere.
我开玩笑呢，放松点儿
I'm kidding. Lighten up.
你收到这个了吗？这备忘录写的不错，虽然年头久了点儿，但内容很好
You got one of these? It's a great memo. It's an oldie but a goodie.
我让你心跳加速了，是不是？
Got your heart racing, don't I?
我不知道你这样做是想干什么
I don't know what it is you think you're doing.
你觉得我这样做是想干什么？
What do you think I'm doing?
案子结了，我们和解了
The suit's over. We have a deal.
不管那是什么，现在都没用了
Whatever that is, it's meaningless at this point.
你这么认为？这样啊，我还以为你只是提出一个建议方案呢
You think? I must have gotten it wrong. I thought you had a tentative proposal.
我还没想到这些钱都是你给的呢
I didn't realize you'd signed all those checks.
这是个累赘，我有上千本，我拿它们怎么办？
That's a drag. I got a thousand of these. What am I gonna do with them?
我要给马蒂打电话
I'm calling Marty.
好，好啊，打吧，那会是个很好的开始
Good. Good. Do it. That's a great place to start.
让我们看看是谁告诉他亚瑟和安娜·凯泽森联系
Let's find out who told him Arthur was calling Anna Kysersun.
让我们看看是谁窃听的电话
Let's find out who tapped those phones.
这本备忘录，我对其真实性有异议，我强烈怀疑…
This memorandum, even if it's authentic, which I doubt, I highly doubt­
-我知道你对亚瑟做了些什么 -这是受保护的文件，它属于U/North公司
-I know what you did to Arthur -It's protected. It belongs to U/North.
-我知道是你杀了他 -这是律师和客户之间的隐私
-I know you killed him -It's attorney-client privilege.
凯伦，你看，现在，事情不该是这样的
See, now, that's just not the way to go here, Karen.
对于一个这么聪明的人来说，你有点儿不知所措了，是不是？
For such a smart person, you really are lost, aren't you?
谈话结束
This conversation is over.
我不是你该除掉的人，我是你该收买的人
I'm not the guy that you kill. I'm the guy that you buy.
你他妈的瞎到连我是什么人都没看出来？
Are you so fucking blind you don't even see what I am?
我是你整个儿环节上最容易的一环，你还想做了我？
I'm the easiest part of your whole goddamn problem and you're gonna kill me?
你不知道我谁么？我是救火队员，我是跑腿的
Don't you know who I am? I'm a fixer. I'm a bagman.
我经手的人从顺手牵羊的主妇到贪赃枉法的国会议员…
I do everything from shoplifting housewives to bent congressmen­
…你还想做了我？
­and you're gonna kill me?
你想要什么，凯伦？告诉我
What do you need, Karen? Lay it on me.
你想要枪支携带证明？还是想要关于内线交易传票的警告
You want a carry permit? You want a heads-up on an insider-trading subpoena?
我8万块和一纸合同就把亚瑟卖了，你还想做了我？
I sold out Arthur for 80 grand and a contract and you're gonna kill me?
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我想要什么？
What do I want?
我要更多
I want more.
我要不干了
I want out.
有这个，我什么都要
And with this, I want everything.
开个价吧？
Is there a number?
我的要价是10
Ten is a number.
10？10什么？
Ten? Ten what?
1000万？
Ten million?
你觉得我上哪儿搞那1000万去？
Where do you think I'm gonna get 10 million dollars?
你知道这东西哪点好么？
You know what's great about this?
你看到结尾了吗？你看到谁签署的了吗？
Did you read it to the end? You see who signed it?
咱们一起进去问问丹·杰弗瑞…
Let's go in and ask Don Jeffries­
…看看他觉得这个价怎么样
­if he wants to pass the hat for a worthy cause.
还有很多需要商量的内容…
This would have to be a longer conversation­
…我们在别处继续谈
­and would have to take place somewhere else.
哪儿？我车里？
Where? My car?
好吧
All right.
简单点儿，5就行了
I'm gonna make it easy. Let's make it 5.
5百万我就能忘了亚瑟
Five and I'll forget about Arthur.
5百万容易些，好，5百万可以商量
Five is easier. Yeah, 5 is something that we could talk about.
好，还有5百万是为了忘记那468个…
Good. And then the other 5 is to forget about the 468 people­
…被你的除草剂害了的受害者
­that you knocked off with your weed killer.
就到这儿吧，我会和丹谈谈…
Let me finish up this meeting. I'll talk to Don­
我看起来是来谈判的吗？！
Do I look like I'm negotiating?!
凯伦？
Karen?
-等一下 -一切都好么？
-One second -Everything okay?
好吧
Yes.
1000万美元，我选银行，离岸帐户，立即支付
Ten million dollars. Bank of my choosing. Offshore. Immediately.
-好的 -说一遍！
-Yes -Say it!
1000万美元，你选帐户，马上就给
Ten million dollars, your account, the moment this meeting is through.
-凯伦！大家都等着呢 -我就来，丹
-Karen! Everyone's waiting -I'm coming, Don.
成交了
You have a deal.
你被耍了
You're so fucked.
什么？
What?
-你被耍了 -你什么意思？
-You're fucked -What do you mean?
-猜猜看啊 -有事吗？
-Take a wild guess -Is there a problem?
-我不明白 -来让我拍一张“工作”照
-I don't understand -Let me get a picture while I'm at it.
-你不要钱吗？ -自己留着吧，你会用得上的
-You don't want the money? -Keep the money. You'll need it.
这家伙烦着你了吗？
Is this fellow bothering you?
我烦着你了吗？
Am I bothering you?
凯伦，董事会都在里面等着呢，这到底出什么事了？你是谁？
Karen, I've got a board waiting in there. What the helI's going on? Who are you?
我是湿婆，死亡之神
I'm Shiva, the god of death.
罗！罗尼，让保安马上过来
Ron! Ronny, I need security out here immediately.
好的，这儿呢
All right. Here we go.
那个人，抓住那个人
That guy right there, stop him. Grab that guy.
-你们干什么？ -我们是纽约警局的侦探
-What are you doing? -We're detectives with the N.Y.P.D.
跟我们过来，我们会解释的
Come back with us and we'll explain everything.
看看她，看看她需不需要急救人员
Check on her. Make sure she doesn't need any medical attention.
你们进屋去，任何人都不许离开
You guys go into the ballroom. Nobody leaves.
所有出口都安排人把守
Have your guys cover every exit.
你们能不能解释下到底发生了什么事？
Will you please explain to me what's going on here?
你都录下了？
Did you get all that?
嗯，都录下了
Yeah. Got it.
-你还好吧？ -还好，就是得呼吸点儿新鲜空气
-You okay? -Yeah. Just gotta get some air.
好吧
Sure.
别乱跑，好吧？
Just stay close, okay?
好的
Okay.
我们去哪儿？
So, what are we doing?
开50块钱的路费
Give me 50 dollars' worth.
开就行了
Just drive.